[
	{
		"answerText": "Breaking Bad[10]  Using his knowledge of chemistry, Walter is able to produce a 99.1% pure form of methamphetamine that is this color because of his usage of methylamine instead of pseudoephedrine.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: A spin-off of this AMC TV series, Better Call Saul, is set to be produced. For 10 points each: [10] Name this TV show that documents the escapades of terminal cancer patient Walter White as he struggles to provide for his family through the dealing of methamphetamine.",
		"answers": [
			"Breaking",
			"Bad",
			"10",
			"Using",
			"his",
			"knowledge",
			"chemistry",
			"Walter",
			"able",
			"to",
			"produce",
			"99",
			"1%",
			"pure",
			"form",
			"methamphetamine",
			"that",
			"this",
			"color",
			"because",
			"usage",
			"methylamine",
			"instead",
			"pseudoephedrine"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Wicked[10] This lead singer in the Broadway production of Wicked performed as the green-faced witch Elphaba in \"Defying Gravity.\" John Travolta infamously mispronounced her name at the 2014 Academy Awards.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this musical, Prince Fiyero advises his fellow students that they should stop studying and live the \"unexamined life\". For 10 points each: [10] Name this 2003 musical with the number \"Dancing Through Life\", in which Fiyero wins the admiration of many female students, including a girl whom Boq asks to a dance. She convinces Boq to ask Nessarose instead.",
		"answers": [
			"Wicked",
			"10",
			"This",
			"lead",
			"singer",
			"in",
			"Broadway",
			"production",
			"performed",
			"as",
			"green-faced",
			"witch",
			"Elphaba",
			"Defying",
			"Gravity",
			"John",
			"Travolta",
			"infamously",
			"mispronounced",
			"her",
			"name",
			"at",
			"2014",
			"Academy",
			"Awards"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yankee Stadium[10] This stadium located in the Bronx, New York was dubbed \"The House that Ruth Built\" due to Babe Ruth's many impressive games played in it. It takes its name from its home team.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 11 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these cathedrals of America's pastime: baseball stadiums. [10] This stadium located in the Bronx, New York was dubbed \"The House that Ruth Built\" due to Babe Ruth's many impressive games played in it. It takes its name from its home team.",
		"answers": [
			"Yankee",
			"Stadium",
			"10",
			"This",
			"stadium",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Bronx",
			"New",
			"York",
			"was",
			"dubbed",
			"The",
			"House",
			"that",
			"Ruth",
			"Built",
			"due",
			"to",
			"Babe",
			"Ruth's",
			"many",
			"impressive",
			"games",
			"played",
			"It",
			"takes",
			"its",
			"name",
			"from",
			"home",
			"team"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Rap God\"[10] Rap God was a song by this rapper, who occasionally performs under his alter-ego, Slim Shady. Singles from his 2010 album Recovery include \"Lose Yourself\" and \"Love the Way You Lie,\" which features Rihanna.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 4 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The artist of this song was going to go easy on us not to hurt our feelings, but changes his mind after he realizes that he's only going to get this one chance. For 10 points each: [10] Name this song in which the artist spews out a long string of unintelligible jibber-jabber before declaring that he's beginning to feel like the title figure.",
		"answers": [
			"Rap",
			"God",
			"10",
			"was",
			"song",
			"by",
			"this",
			"rapper",
			"who",
			"occasionally",
			"performs",
			"under",
			"his",
			"alter-ego",
			"Slim",
			"Shady",
			"Singles",
			"from",
			"2010",
			"album",
			"Recovery",
			"include",
			"Lose",
			"Yourself",
			"and",
			"Love",
			"Way",
			"You",
			"Lie",
			"which",
			"features",
			"Rihanna"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "zombies [accept equivalents like the undead][10] This video game follows Joel and Ellie, who fight Cordyceps-infected zombies as they traverse a post-apocalyptic landscape to find the Fireflies.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 1 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: John Marston fights these beings in a Red Dead Redemption downloadable pack. For 10 points each: [10] Name these beings who drop rotten flesh in Minecraft and name a special mode in the Call of Duty series. They are the principal enemies in Left 4 Dead, Resident Evil, and The Walking Dead. ",
		"answers": [
			"zombies",
			"equivalents",
			"undead",
			"10",
			"This",
			"video",
			"game",
			"follows",
			"Joel",
			"and",
			"Ellie",
			"who",
			"fight",
			"Cordyceps-infected",
			"as",
			"they",
			"traverse",
			"post-apocalyptic",
			"landscape",
			"to",
			"find",
			"Fireflies"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigur Rós (\"see-uhr rose\")[10] Sigur Rós collaborated with this English band on Merce Cunningham's Split Sides. Headed by Thom Yorke, they released the song \"Creep\" and the albums Kid A, OK Computer, and In Rainbows.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 6 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This band exhibited a more aggressive metal sound in their recent album Kveikur. For 10 points each: [10] Name this post-rock band led by Jonsi, who plays bowed guitar and sings ethereal vocals in Vonlenska. Their albums include Agaetis byrjun (\"OW-guy-tis bee-ARR-yun\"), Takk, and Valtari. ",
		"answers": [
			"Sigur",
			"Rós",
			"see-uhr",
			"rose",
			"10",
			"collaborated",
			"with",
			"this",
			"English",
			"band",
			"Merce",
			"Cunningham's",
			"Split",
			"Sides",
			"Headed",
			"by",
			"Thom",
			"Yorke",
			"they",
			"released",
			"song",
			"Creep",
			"and",
			"albums",
			"Kid",
			"A",
			"OK",
			"Computer",
			"In",
			"Rainbows"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Little Prince[10] This author of The Little Prince and Southern Mail expanded on his experience as a stranded aviator in the Sahara Desert in his memoir Wind, Sand, and Stars.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 21 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Its narrator begins by recalling his childhood sketch of a boa constrictor devouring an elephant. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this novel in which a wandering boy who leaves the asteroid B-612 because he does not know how to love his rose. He meets the narrator, now a full-fledged pilot whose plane has broken down in the Sahara.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Little",
			"Prince",
			"10",
			"This",
			"author",
			"and",
			"Southern",
			"Mail",
			"expanded",
			"his",
			"experience",
			"as",
			"stranded",
			"aviator",
			"in",
			"Sahara",
			"Desert",
			"memoir",
			"Wind",
			"Sand",
			"Stars"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lorde (accept Ella Yelich-O'Connor)[10] That single by Lorde is this song that advocates against lavish lifestyles in its chorus: \"that kind of luxe just ain't for us / we crave a different kind of buzz.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 3 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The chorus of one song by this artist begins \"Baby be the class clown/ I'll be the beauty queen in tears.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this sixteen-year-old artist from New Zealand, whose singles include \"Tennis Court\" and one that begins \"I've never seen a diamond in the flesh.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Lorde",
			"Ella",
			"Yelich-O'Connor",
			"10",
			"That",
			"single",
			"by",
			"this",
			"song",
			"that",
			"advocates",
			"against",
			"lavish",
			"lifestyles",
			"in",
			"its",
			"chorus:",
			"luxe",
			"just",
			"ain't",
			"for",
			"us",
			"/",
			"we",
			"crave",
			"different",
			"buzz"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Orleans Saints [accept either][10] This tight end for the Saints played basketball in college. In 2011, he broke the receiving yards record for a tight end, only to have his record broken later that day by Rob Gronkowski.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Sean Payton is the coach for this NFC South team led by quarterback Drew Brees. For 10 points each: [10] Name this team that plays in the Mercedes-Benz Superdome and is known for their fans' expression, \"Who Dat?\"",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Orleans",
			"Saints",
			"10",
			"This",
			"tight",
			"end",
			"for",
			"played",
			"basketball",
			"in",
			"college",
			"In",
			"2011",
			"he",
			"broke",
			"receiving",
			"yards",
			"record",
			"only",
			"to",
			"have",
			"his",
			"broken",
			"later",
			"that",
			"day",
			"by",
			"Rob",
			"Gronkowski"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hushpuppy[10] Hushpuppy is the main character of this Benh Zeitlin film set on a Louisiana island devastated by a hurricane. Zeitlin and Wallis received Academy Award nominations for their work in this film.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 10 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This character listens to her father's last heartbeat after negotiating a peace with the Aurochs. For 10 points each: [10] Name this protagonist of a 2012 indie film played by Quvenzhane Wallis who lives in \"The Bathtub\" with her father Wink.",
		"answers": [
			"Hushpuppy",
			"10",
			"main",
			"character",
			"this",
			"Benh",
			"Zeitlin",
			"film",
			"set",
			"Louisiana",
			"island",
			"devastated",
			"by",
			"hurricane",
			"and",
			"Wallis",
			"received",
			"Academy",
			"Award",
			"nominations",
			"for",
			"their",
			"work",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Duke Nukem Forever[10] After Episode 2 of the second installment in this series came out, the lack of any information about the next installment featuring Gordon Freeman helped lead to a joke that Valve can't count to three.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 16 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these video games we've been waiting a long time for: [10] This title became for a long time the most infamous example of vaporware, with its previous \"3D\" installation coming out in 1996. It was finally released in 2011, allowing its muscle-toting, bubblegum chewing action figure to see the light of day once again.",
		"answers": [
			"Duke",
			"Nukem",
			"Forever",
			"10",
			"After",
			"Episode",
			"2",
			"second",
			"installment",
			"in",
			"this",
			"series",
			"came",
			"out",
			"lack",
			"information",
			"about",
			"next",
			"featuring",
			"Gordon",
			"Freeman",
			"helped",
			"lead",
			"to",
			"joke",
			"that",
			"Valve",
			"can't",
			"count",
			"three"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "House of Cards[10] House of Cards airs exclusively on this online streaming site, that controversially split its rental and streaming services.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 7 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This show stars Kevin Spacey as House Majority Whip Frank Underwood. For 10 points each: [10] Name this online series focusing on the efforts of Underwood to undermine the government after getting denied for Secretary of State.",
		"answers": [
			"House",
			"Cards",
			"10",
			"airs",
			"exclusively",
			"this",
			"online",
			"streaming",
			"site",
			"that",
			"controversially",
			"split",
			"its",
			"rental",
			"and",
			"services"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "James Harden[10] Harden was traded to the Houston Rockets from this team, which reached the 2012 NBA Finals behind Kevin Durant and Russell Westbrook.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 18 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This NBA player's beard has inspired multiple Facebook and Twitter accounts, for 10 points each: [10] Name this shooting guard who was drafted out of Arizona State in 2009 by his former team, but now plays alongside Jeremy Lin in Houston.",
		"answers": [
			"James",
			"Harden",
			"10",
			"was",
			"traded",
			"to",
			"Houston",
			"Rockets",
			"from",
			"this",
			"team",
			"which",
			"reached",
			"2012",
			"NBA",
			"Finals",
			"behind",
			"Kevin",
			"Durant",
			"and",
			"Russell",
			"Westbrook"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Flash[10] This third incarnation of the Flash took over after Barry Allen was killed during the Crisis on Infinite Earths. He was the nephew of Barry's wife Iris.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 16 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Incarnations of this superhero have included Jay Garrick and Barry Allen. For 10 points each: [10] Name this \"Scarlet Speedster\" from the DC Comics universe who posses super-speed and has a lightning bolt insignia.",
		"answers": [
			"Flash",
			"10",
			"This",
			"third",
			"incarnation",
			"took",
			"over",
			"after",
			"Barry",
			"Allen",
			"was",
			"killed",
			"during",
			"Crisis",
			"Infinite",
			"Earths",
			"He",
			"nephew",
			"Barry's",
			"wife",
			"Iris"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Death Cab For Cutie[10] In The Motorcycle Diaries, this character swims across the Amazon River to be with some lepers on his birthday. His visage is commonly seen on T-shirts.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 4 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about people who find themselves separated by bodies of water.  [10] This band's \"Transatlanticism\", about a relationship separated by the Atlantic, has a chorus of \"I need you so much closer.\" Other songs by them include \"I Will Possess Your Heart\" and \"I Will Follow You Into the Dark.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Death",
			"Cab",
			"For",
			"Cutie",
			"10",
			"In",
			"The",
			"Motorcycle",
			"Diaries",
			"this",
			"character",
			"swims",
			"across",
			"Amazon",
			"River",
			"to",
			"be",
			"with",
			"some",
			"lepers",
			"his",
			"birthday",
			"His",
			"visage",
			"commonly",
			"seen",
			"T-shirts"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Firefly[10] Centering around the exploits of the dysfunctional Bluth family, new episodes of this comedy starring Jason Bateman will start airing on Netflix in the spring of 2013, seven years after it was originally cancelled by Fox.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 1 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Fox network has cancelled some of the best TV shows of all time. Name three of them, for 10 points each: [10] Starring Nathan Fillion and Morena Baccarin, this space western epic acquired so much post-cancellation support that its story was allowed to continue in the feature film Serenity.",
		"answers": [
			"Firefly",
			"10",
			"Centering",
			"around",
			"exploits",
			"dysfunctional",
			"Bluth",
			"family",
			"new",
			"episodes",
			"this",
			"comedy",
			"starring",
			"Jason",
			"Bateman",
			"will",
			"start",
			"airing",
			"Netflix",
			"in",
			"spring",
			"2013",
			"seven",
			"years",
			"after",
			"was",
			"originally",
			"cancelled",
			"by",
			"Fox"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Firefly[10] Centering around the exploits of the dysfunctional Bluth family, new episodes of this comedy starring Jason Bateman will start airing on Netflix in the spring of 2013, seven years after it was originally cancelled by Fox.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 1 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Fox network has cancelled some of the best TV shows of all time. Name three of them, for 10 points each: [10] Starring Nathan Fillion and Morena Baccarin, this space western epic acquired so much post-cancellation support that its story was allowed to continue in the feature film Serenity.",
		"answers": [
			"Firefly",
			"10",
			"Centering",
			"around",
			"exploits",
			"dysfunctional",
			"Bluth",
			"family",
			"new",
			"episodes",
			"this",
			"comedy",
			"starring",
			"Jason",
			"Bateman",
			"will",
			"start",
			"airing",
			"Netflix",
			"in",
			"spring",
			"2013",
			"seven",
			"years",
			"after",
			"was",
			"originally",
			"cancelled",
			"by",
			"Fox"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Back in Black[10] Back in Black is a song by this Australian band, famous for other songs such as Shoot to Thrill and Highway to Hell.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 2 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this song, famous for its intro guitar riff, whose singer has \"hit the sack\" and is \"glad\" since he's \"been too long\".",
		"answers": [
			"Back",
			"in",
			"Black",
			"10",
			"song",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Australian",
			"band",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"other",
			"songs",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Shoot",
			"to",
			"Thrill",
			"and",
			"Highway",
			"Hell"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kellogg's Frosted Flakes[10]  This fictional serial killer is depicted in The Silence of the Lambs. In the movie adaptation, he is played by Anthony Hopkins and claimed to have eaten a census taker's liver with \"some fava beans and a nice chianti\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 11 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Kellogg cereal known as Zucaritas in Latin America is a good source of Vitamin D. Its namesake flattened corn pieces are coated in sugar, and Tony the Tiger insists that they are delicious.",
		"answers": [
			"Kellogg's",
			"Frosted",
			"Flakes",
			"10",
			"This",
			"fictional",
			"serial",
			"killer",
			"depicted",
			"in",
			"The",
			"Silence",
			"Lambs",
			"In",
			"movie",
			"adaptation",
			"he",
			"played",
			"by",
			"Anthony",
			"Hopkins",
			"and",
			"claimed",
			"to",
			"have",
			"eaten",
			"census",
			"taker's",
			"liver",
			"with",
			"some",
			"fava",
			"beans",
			"nice",
			"chianti"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Song 2\"[10]  Blur clashed with this band whose members include the Gallagher brothers. Their songs include \"Rock 'N' Roll Star\" from Definitely Maybe and \"Wonderwall\" from [What's the Story] Morning Glory.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Britpop song from Blur's self-titled album includes the lines \"I got my head checked\" and \"Pleased to meet you\". Its raucous chorus sees Damon Albarn yell \"Woo-hoo!\".",
		"answers": [
			"Song",
			"2",
			"10",
			"Blur",
			"clashed",
			"with",
			"this",
			"band",
			"whose",
			"members",
			"include",
			"Gallagher",
			"brothers",
			"Their",
			"songs",
			"Rock",
			"'N'",
			"Roll",
			"Star",
			"from",
			"Definitely",
			"Maybe",
			"and",
			"Wonderwall",
			"What's",
			"Story",
			"Morning",
			"Glory"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mojo Jojo (\"mo-jo JO-JO!\")[10]  Mojo Jojo is the main antagonist of this animated TV show broadcast by Cartoon Network. It centers around the superhero trio of Blossom, Bubbles and Buttercup in the city of Townsville.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this purple-caped chimpanzee with green skin and a huge brain. He creates the Rowdyruff Boys to counter his archenemies.",
		"answers": [
			"Mojo",
			"Jojo",
			"mo-jo",
			"JO-JO!",
			"10",
			"main",
			"antagonist",
			"this",
			"animated",
			"TV",
			"show",
			"broadcast",
			"by",
			"Cartoon",
			"Network",
			"It",
			"centers",
			"around",
			"superhero",
			"trio",
			"Blossom",
			"Bubbles",
			"and",
			"Buttercup",
			"in",
			"city",
			"Townsville"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Inigo Montoya[10]  Inigo Montoya and Fezzik accompany Westley on his quest to save Buttercup in this film that notably cuts the ambiguous ending of the William Goldman novel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 15 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Spaniard who is finally able to kill Count Rugen. He does so while repeating a line in which he introduces himself and states \"You killed my father. Prepare to die.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Inigo",
			"Montoya",
			"10",
			"and",
			"Fezzik",
			"accompany",
			"Westley",
			"his",
			"quest",
			"to",
			"save",
			"Buttercup",
			"in",
			"this",
			"film",
			"that"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Marlon Brando Jr.[10]  This actor gained popularity after he appeared as the moody Cal Trask in Kazan's East of Eden. He died in a car crash a month after the release of Rebel Without a Cause, in which he played the angsty teenager Jim Stark.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 18 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Kazan launched the career of this actor who played Stanley Kowalski in A Streetcar Named Desire and Terry Malloy in On the Waterfront. His other roles include motorcycle gang leader Johnny Strabler and Vito Corleone.",
		"answers": [
			"Marlon",
			"Brando",
			"Jr",
			"10",
			"This",
			"actor",
			"gained",
			"popularity",
			"after",
			"he",
			"appeared",
			"as",
			"moody",
			"Cal",
			"Trask",
			"in",
			"Kazan's",
			"East",
			"Eden",
			"He",
			"died",
			"car",
			"crash",
			"month",
			"release",
			"Rebel",
			"Without",
			"Cause",
			"which",
			"played",
			"angsty",
			"teenager",
			"Jim",
			"Stark"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Solid Snake [accept David or Iroquois Pliskin][10]  This offensive class in Team Fortress 2 wields a Rocket Launcher as his primary weapon. He is fond of crazily waving around his melee weapon, a shovel, and lecturing on Sun Tzu, who he believes invented warfare.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This protagonist of the Metal Gear series uses a severely overpowered Grenade Launcher as his Final Smash in Super Smash Bros. Brawl. His job as a spy causes him to frequently hide within cardboard boxes.",
		"answers": [
			"Solid",
			"Snake",
			"David",
			"Iroquois",
			"Pliskin",
			"10",
			"This",
			"offensive",
			"class",
			"in",
			"Team",
			"Fortress",
			"2",
			"wields",
			"Rocket",
			"Launcher",
			"as",
			"his",
			"primary",
			"weapon",
			"He",
			"fond",
			"crazily",
			"waving",
			"around",
			"melee",
			"shovel",
			"and",
			"lecturing",
			"Sun",
			"Tzu",
			"who",
			"he",
			"believes",
			"invented",
			"warfare"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Taylor Swift[10]  The band Red fronted by Michael Barnes performs this genre of music. This subgenre of rock features groups like Relient K, Kutless and Skillet, whose 2000 album Ardent Worship contains the track \"Angels Fall Down\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This singer-songwriter released her album Red in 2012, which contains such tracks like \"We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together\". Her 2008 album, Fearless, contains \"Love Story\" and \"You Belong with Me\".",
		"answers": [
			"Taylor",
			"Swift",
			"10",
			"The",
			"band",
			"Red",
			"fronted",
			"by",
			"Michael",
			"Barnes",
			"performs",
			"this",
			"genre",
			"music",
			"This",
			"subgenre",
			"rock",
			"features",
			"groups",
			"Relient",
			"K",
			"Kutless",
			"and",
			"Skillet",
			"whose",
			"2000",
			"album",
			"Ardent",
			"Worship",
			"contains",
			"track",
			"Angels",
			"Fall",
			"Down"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "H.A.M.M.E.R.[10]  In this song, MC Hammer claims you must \"break it down\" since it is \"Hammer time\" and that he is \"dope on the floor and magic on the mic\". He proposes that this song will make listeners thinner since he is \"makin' 'em sweat\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 15 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  In the Marvel universe, Norman Osborn reforms S.H.I.E.L.D. into this organization after Tony Stark's security system is compromised by the secret Skrull invasion of Earth. This organization is ultimately dissolved following the failed siege of Asgard.",
		"answers": [
			"H",
			"A",
			"M",
			"E",
			"R",
			"10",
			"In",
			"this",
			"song",
			"MC",
			"Hammer",
			"claims",
			"you",
			"must",
			"break",
			"down",
			"since",
			"time",
			"and",
			"that",
			"he",
			"dope",
			"floor",
			"magic",
			"mic",
			"He",
			"proposes",
			"will",
			"make",
			"listeners",
			"thinner",
			"makin'",
			"'em",
			"sweat"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Dragon Ball Z [or Doragon Boru; accept Dragon Ball suffixed by anything][10]  Hirasawa Yui joins the Light Music club and befriends bassist Mio Akiyama and drummer Tainaka Ritsu in this anime. They later form the band Ho-Kago Tea Time which performs at Sakura High School.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 11 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Goku the Saiyan travels around the world learning martial arts, beating up enemies like Vegeta and Piccolo and searching for the title magical orbs in this 291-episode series.",
		"answers": [
			"Dragon",
			"Ball",
			"Z",
			"Doragon",
			"Boru",
			"suffixed",
			"by",
			"anything",
			"10",
			"Hirasawa",
			"Yui",
			"joins",
			"Light",
			"Music",
			"club",
			"and",
			"befriends",
			"bassist",
			"Mio",
			"Akiyama",
			"drummer",
			"Tainaka",
			"Ritsu",
			"in",
			"this",
			"anime",
			"They",
			"later",
			"form",
			"band",
			"Ho-Kago",
			"Tea",
			"Time",
			"which",
			"performs",
			"at",
			"Sakura",
			"High",
			"School"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cowboy Bebop [or Kauboi Bibappu][10]  This Joss Whedon-created series centers around the eccentric crew of Serenity, including the pilot Wash, the mercenary Jayne, and the somewhat unstable River, all led by Captain Malcolm Reynolds.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  An iconic scene from this animated series is the confrontation with Vicious in a church. It follows the bounty hunter Spike Spiegel, who is joined by Edward, Faye Valentine, Jet Black, and the data dog Ein.",
		"answers": [
			"Cowboy",
			"Bebop",
			"Kauboi",
			"Bibappu",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Joss",
			"Whedon-created",
			"series",
			"centers",
			"around",
			"eccentric",
			"crew",
			"Serenity",
			"including",
			"pilot",
			"Wash",
			"mercenary",
			"Jayne",
			"and",
			"somewhat",
			"unstable",
			"River",
			"all",
			"led",
			"by",
			"Captain",
			"Malcolm",
			"Reynolds"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "University of Kentucky Wildcats [or UK][10]  Calipari has been heavily criticized for his recruiting efforts at Kentucky, which focus on players that seek to take advantage of this rule.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 6 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this college basketball team coached by John Calipari.",
		"answers": [
			"University",
			"Kentucky",
			"Wildcats",
			"UK",
			"10",
			"Calipari",
			"has",
			"been",
			"heavily",
			"criticized",
			"for",
			"his",
			"recruiting",
			"efforts",
			"at",
			"which",
			"focus",
			"players",
			"that",
			"seek",
			"to",
			"take",
			"advantage",
			"this",
			"rule"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Michael Phelps[10]  This athlete, at seventeen, was the second-youngest member of the Olympic team. At the Olympics, she swept the backstroke events, and now holds the world record for the women's 100-meter backstroke.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round13.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man hails from Baltimore, Maryland, and his signature event is the 200 butterfly. He currently holds the world record for most gold medals won at the Olympics.",
		"answers": [
			"Michael",
			"Phelps",
			"10",
			"This",
			"athlete",
			"at",
			"seventeen",
			"was",
			"second-youngest",
			"member",
			"Olympic",
			"team",
			"At",
			"Olympics",
			"she",
			"swept",
			"backstroke",
			"events",
			"and",
			"now",
			"holds",
			"world",
			"record",
			"for",
			"women's",
			"100-meter"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The King's Speech[10]  This actor played the speech therapist Lionel Logue in The King's Speech. He is also known for playing the character of Barbosa in The Pirates of the Caribbean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 9 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This 2010 film starred Colin Firth as King George VI as he works to overcome his stutter with the help of a speech therapist. It won seven British Academy Film Awards, including Best Picture.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"King's",
			"Speech",
			"10",
			"This",
			"actor",
			"played",
			"speech",
			"therapist",
			"Lionel",
			"Logue",
			"in",
			"He",
			"also",
			"known",
			"for",
			"playing",
			"character",
			"Barbosa",
			"Pirates",
			"Caribbean"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Back in Black[10]  Back in Black is a song by this Australian band, famous for other songs such as Shoot to Thrill and Highway to Hell.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this song, famous for its intro guitar riff, whose singer has \"hit the sack\" and is \"glad\" since he's \"been too long\".",
		"answers": [
			"Back",
			"in",
			"Black",
			"10",
			"song",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Australian",
			"band",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"other",
			"songs",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Shoot",
			"to",
			"Thrill",
			"and",
			"Highway",
			"Hell"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "San Francisco[10]  McDonald's still hasn't re-opened a franchise in this country, due to the low purchasing power of the krona. This nation is governed by the Althing.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 21 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  In 2010, led by Eric Mar, this California city banned the giving of toys along with Happy Meals. It later unrelatedly tried to ban circumcision, but the measure never made it onto the ballot.\n",
		"answers": [
			"San",
			"Francisco",
			"10",
			"McDonald's",
			"still",
			"hasn't",
			"re-opened",
			"franchise",
			"in",
			"this",
			"country",
			"due",
			"to",
			"low",
			"purchasing",
			"power",
			"krona",
			"This",
			"nation",
			"governed",
			"by",
			"Althing"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Mean Girls[10]  Lindsay Lohan plays both of the twins Hallie and Annie who attempt to bring their divorced mother and father back together in this remake of a 1961 film.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 20 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This teen comedy explained the life of Cady Heron and her adventures with the Regina-led Plastics, who wear pink on Wednesdays.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Mean",
			"Girls",
			"10",
			"Lindsay",
			"Lohan",
			"plays",
			"both",
			"twins",
			"Hallie",
			"and",
			"Annie",
			"who",
			"attempt",
			"to",
			"bring",
			"their",
			"divorced",
			"mother",
			"father",
			"back",
			"together",
			"in",
			"this",
			"remake",
			"1961",
			"film"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "placekicker[10]  This kicker made the tying and winning field goals for the Patriots in the \"Tuck Rule Game,\" and later made the winning kicks in Super Bowls XXXVI (36) and XXXVIII (38). He now plays for the Colts.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 16 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this position in American football, which is responsible for getting a ball through the uprights to make a field goal or get the extra point after a touchdown.",
		"answers": [
			"placekicker",
			"10",
			"This",
			"kicker",
			"made",
			"tying",
			"and",
			"winning",
			"field",
			"goals",
			"for",
			"Patriots",
			"in",
			"Tuck",
			"Rule",
			"Game",
			"later",
			"kicks",
			"Super",
			"Bowls",
			"XXXVI",
			"36",
			"XXXVIII",
			"38",
			"He",
			"now",
			"plays",
			"Colts"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Key and Peele[10]  Key and Peele have also done multiple skits which mention the teeth of these animals, a talking one of which is voiced by Eddie Murphy in Shrek.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 13 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this show on Comedy Central in which two black comedians perform skits like Dueling Hats, Substitute Teacher, and Pizza Order.",
		"answers": [
			"Key",
			"and",
			"Peele",
			"10",
			"have",
			"also",
			"done",
			"multiple",
			"skits",
			"which",
			"teeth",
			"these",
			"animals",
			"talking",
			"one",
			"voiced",
			"by",
			"Eddie",
			"Murphy",
			"in",
			"Shrek"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Ferris Bueller (accept either)[10]  At the climax of the film, Cameron causes a red one of these objects owned by his father to go flying out the window and land broken on the ground.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 3 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this character who takes a 'day off' in a John Hughes film, skipping school with his friends Cameron and Sloane.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Ferris",
			"Bueller",
			"10",
			"At",
			"climax",
			"film",
			"Cameron",
			"causes",
			"red",
			"one",
			"these",
			"objects",
			"owned",
			"by",
			"his",
			"father",
			"to",
			"go",
			"flying",
			"out",
			"window",
			"and",
			"land",
			"broken",
			"ground"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Millenium Falcon[10]  This captain of the Falcon is inseparable from his Wookie friend Chewbacca, the ship's first mate. In the original Star Wars movie, this smuggler played by Harrison Ford shot Greedo first.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this spaceship, once owned by Lando Calrissian. It was able to make the Kessel run in less than twelve parsecs.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Millenium",
			"Falcon",
			"10",
			"This",
			"captain",
			"inseparable",
			"from",
			"his",
			"Wookie",
			"friend",
			"Chewbacca",
			"ship's",
			"first",
			"mate",
			"In",
			"original",
			"Star",
			"Wars",
			"movie",
			"this",
			"smuggler",
			"played",
			"by",
			"Harrison",
			"Ford",
			"shot",
			"Greedo"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "2 chainz (accept Tauheed Epps or Tity Boi)[10]  2 chainz raps alongside this performer in \"Birthday Song\".  He famously interrupted Taylor Swift at the Video Music Awards and to note that \"Beyonce had one of the best videos of all time\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this rapper, who appeared in \"No Lie\"  along with Drake where he says that he is \"smoking on that gas.\" His current stage name is derived from his trademark jewelry, and he formed Playaz Circle with his friend Dolla Boy.",
		"answers": [
			"2",
			"chainz",
			"Tauheed",
			"Epps",
			"Tity",
			"Boi",
			"10",
			"raps",
			"alongside",
			"this",
			"performer",
			"in",
			"Birthday",
			"Song",
			"He",
			"famously",
			"interrupted",
			"Taylor",
			"Swift",
			"at",
			"Video",
			"Music",
			"Awards",
			"and",
			"to"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Love the Way You Lie\"[10]  This rapper collaborated with Rihanna on \"Love the Way You Lie.\" His latest album, Recovery, features hit singles such as \"Not Afraid,\" and one of his most successful albums was 1999's The Slim Shady LP.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 21 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this song in which the main artist claims that their crazy relationship is \"what happens when a tornado meets a volcano,\" but never seems to tell the truth.",
		"answers": [
			"Love",
			"Way",
			"You",
			"Lie",
			"10",
			"This",
			"rapper",
			"collaborated",
			"with",
			"Rihanna",
			"His",
			"latest",
			"album",
			"Recovery",
			"features",
			"hit",
			"singles",
			"such",
			"as"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Minecraft[10]  This battle arena game, developed by Riot Games, features a spawn point called the \"spawning pool\" and includes such features as Nexuses and Turrets.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This indie game developed by Mojang Inc. was created by Markus Persson, also known as Notch. It features one by one meter blocks to form the gameplay world.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Minecraft",
			"10",
			"This",
			"battle",
			"arena",
			"game",
			"developed",
			"by",
			"Riot",
			"Games",
			"features",
			"spawn",
			"point",
			"called",
			"spawning",
			"pool",
			"and",
			"includes",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Nexuses",
			"Turrets"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Citizen Kane (or Charles Foster Kane)[10]  Citizen Kane was directed by this man, who also played the title role. He also famously read The War of the Worlds on the radio, inciting a small panic.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 3 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this media magnate, the title character of the film in which he appears, who dies while dropping a snowglobe and saying the word \"Rosebud.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Citizen",
			"Kane",
			"Charles",
			"Foster",
			"10",
			"was",
			"directed",
			"by",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"also",
			"played",
			"title",
			"role",
			"He",
			"famously",
			"read",
			"The",
			"War",
			"Worlds",
			"radio",
			"inciting",
			"small",
			"panic"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Walking Dead[10]  This network broadcasts The Walking Dead, Mad Men, and Breaking Bad.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 19 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this show in which Rick Grimes leads a group on the run from zombies in northern Georgia.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Walking",
			"Dead",
			"10",
			"This",
			"network",
			"broadcasts",
			"Mad",
			"Men",
			"and",
			"Breaking",
			"Bad"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Downton Abbey[10]  This third cousin of the Earl becomes the heir presumptive to the estate after the deaths of the other heirs on the RMS Titanic. He later marries Mary.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This television series centers around the title fictional estate set in Yorkshire, England and focuses on the aristocratic Crawley family and their servants.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Downton",
			"Abbey",
			"10",
			"This",
			"third",
			"cousin",
			"Earl",
			"becomes",
			"heir",
			"presumptive",
			"to",
			"estate",
			"after",
			"deaths",
			"other",
			"heirs",
			"RMS",
			"Titanic",
			"He",
			"later",
			"marries",
			"Mary"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic[10]  This cyan-colored pegasus pony is known for her daring flight stunts and seeks to join an elite group of pony flyers called the \"Wonderbolts\". She is the only pony known to have successfully completed a \"sonic rainboom.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this television series, the first episode of which sees Twilight Sparkle and her friends unite the Elements of Harmony to save Equestria from Nightmare Moon.",
		"answers": [
			"My",
			"Little",
			"Pony:",
			"Friendship",
			"Magic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"cyan-colored",
			"pegasus",
			"pony",
			"known",
			"for",
			"her",
			"daring",
			"flight",
			"stunts",
			"and",
			"seeks",
			"to",
			"join",
			"an",
			"elite",
			"group",
			"flyers",
			"called",
			"Wonderbolts",
			"She",
			"only",
			"have",
			"successfully",
			"completed",
			"sonic",
			"rainboom"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stephen Colbert[10]  Colbert's best friend for six months was this man, who was part of the cast of SNL before getting his own late-night show on NBC. The house band for his show is The Roots.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 9 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man got his start on the Daily Show, and now hosts his own namesake Report [\"ruh-PORE\"]on Comedy Central, a parody of Fox News opinion shows.",
		"answers": [
			"Stephen",
			"Colbert",
			"10",
			"Colbert's",
			"best",
			"friend",
			"for",
			"six",
			"months",
			"was",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"part",
			"cast",
			"SNL",
			"getting",
			"his",
			"own",
			"late-night",
			"show",
			"NBC",
			"The",
			"house",
			"band",
			"Roots"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: The Princess Bride[10]  This Reiner film focuses on the murder of PFC William Santiago under a \"code red\" ordered by Colonel Jessep, who informs Kaffee that he \"can't handle the truth.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  \"Wuv, twoo wuv\" is the subject of this comedic film in which Wesley works with Inigo Montoya to rescue Buttercup from Prince Humperdink.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"The",
			"Princess",
			"Bride",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Reiner",
			"film",
			"focuses",
			"murder",
			"PFC",
			"William",
			"Santiago",
			"under",
			"code",
			"red",
			"ordered",
			"by",
			"Colonel",
			"Jessep",
			"who",
			"informs",
			"Kaffee",
			"that",
			"he",
			"can't",
			"handle",
			"truth"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: A Game of Thrones[10]  Lord Eddard Stark is stabbed non-fatally by this Lord Commander of the Kingsguard, the eldest son of Tywin and incestuous lover of Cersei.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 9 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This first novel in \"A Song of Ice and Fire\" details the reign and death of King Robert I Baratheon.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"A",
			"Game",
			"Thrones",
			"10",
			"Lord",
			"Eddard",
			"Stark",
			"stabbed",
			"non-fatally",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Commander",
			"Kingsguard",
			"eldest",
			"son",
			"Tywin",
			"and",
			"incestuous",
			"lover",
			"Cersei"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Oliver Stanley \"Olly\" Murs[10] Murs came in second on 6th season of this show's British version. The boy band One Direction was formed on  this talent-search show, created by Simon Cowell years after American Idol.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 5 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In one song by this musician, he declares \"I swear you're giving me a heart attack\" right before singing the title  word. For 10 points each: [10] Name this singer whose song \"Troublemaker\" features Flo Rida. His singles \"Heart Skips a Beat\" and \"Dance  with Me Tonight\" also topped the British charts.",
		"answers": [
			"Oliver",
			"Stanley",
			"Olly",
			"Murs",
			"10",
			"came",
			"in",
			"second",
			"6th",
			"season",
			"this",
			"show's",
			"British",
			"version",
			"The",
			"boy",
			"band",
			"One",
			"Direction",
			"was",
			"formed",
			"talent-search",
			"show",
			"created",
			"by",
			"Simon",
			"Cowell",
			"years",
			"after",
			"American",
			"Idol"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Oliver Stanley \"Olly\" Murs[10] Murs came in second on 6th season of this show's British version. The boy band One Direction was formed on  this talent-search show, created by Simon Cowell years after American Idol.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 5 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In one song by this musician, he declares \"I swear you're giving me a heart attack\" right before singing the title  word. For 10 points each: [10] Name this singer whose song \"Troublemaker\" features Flo Rida. His singles \"Heart Skips a Beat\" and \"Dance  with Me Tonight\" also topped the British charts.",
		"answers": [
			"Oliver",
			"Stanley",
			"Olly",
			"Murs",
			"10",
			"came",
			"in",
			"second",
			"6th",
			"season",
			"this",
			"show's",
			"British",
			"version",
			"The",
			"boy",
			"band",
			"One",
			"Direction",
			"was",
			"formed",
			"talent-search",
			"show",
			"created",
			"by",
			"Simon",
			"Cowell",
			"years",
			"after",
			"American",
			"Idol"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Smashing Pumpkins[10] One former saxophone player for this band was Derek Kwan. This Californian alternative rock band is known  almost entirely for their 2004 single \"The Reason,\" which begins with the line \"I'm not a perfect person.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 10 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some related bands, for 10 points each: [10] This band fronted by Billy Corgan formerly had rhythm guitarist James Iha. Their albums include Siamese  Dream and Mellon Collie and the Infinite Sadness. After reforming in 2005, they released the album Zeitgeist.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Smashing",
			"Pumpkins",
			"10",
			"One",
			"former",
			"saxophone",
			"player",
			"for",
			"this",
			"band",
			"was",
			"Derek",
			"Kwan",
			"This",
			"Californian",
			"alternative",
			"rock",
			"known",
			"almost",
			"entirely",
			"their",
			"2004",
			"single",
			"Reason",
			"which",
			"begins",
			"with",
			"line",
			"I'm"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mewtwo[10] This Pokémon was originally going to be the mascot of the series, but that role was ultimately taken by  Pikachu. It evolves using a Moon Stone into Clefable.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: So you wanna be a master of Pokémon? Then name some. For 10 points each: [10] This Pokémon, number 150, comes earlier in the Pokédex than the Pokémon it was supposedly a clone of.",
		"answers": [
			"Mewtwo",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Pokémon",
			"was",
			"originally",
			"going",
			"to",
			"be",
			"mascot",
			"series",
			"but",
			"that",
			"role",
			"ultimately",
			"taken",
			"by",
			"Pikachu",
			"It",
			"evolves",
			"using",
			"Moon",
			"Stone",
			"into",
			"Clefable"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Seventh Seal [or Det Sjunde Inseglet][10] The Seventh Seal [or Det Sjunde Inseglet]",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: ends with a danse macabre witnessed by Jof, an actor. For 10 points each: [10] Name this film in which Antonius Block, a crusader who returned to a plague-ravaged Sweden, plays chess against Death.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Seventh",
			"Seal",
			"Det",
			"Sjunde",
			"Inseglet",
			"10"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Sopranos[10] This semi-fictional comedy show involves mostly improvised dialogue between characters, and stars Larry David as himself.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 10 | Trash | American | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some HBO shows, for 10 points each: [10] The pilot of this show involves the protagonist meeting with therapist Jennifer Melfi. This most-successful show ever focuses on Tony, a Mafia boss, and his relationship with his work and his family, which the show is named for. ",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Sopranos",
			"10",
			"This",
			"semi-fictional",
			"comedy",
			"show",
			"involves",
			"mostly",
			"improvised",
			"dialogue",
			"between",
			"characters",
			"and",
			"stars",
			"Larry",
			"David",
			"as",
			"himself"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Psych[10] In the series finale of season 3 of Psych, fake psychic Shawn Spencer is challenged by Mr. Yang, a serial killer based on this famous Bay Area serial killer who was active in 60's and 70's California.  A movie based on this killer was released in 2007.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer these seemingly unrelated questions: [10] Starring Dulé Hill and James Roday, the main protagonist of this television show is obsessed with pineapples. The actors playing a pair of detectives for the Santa Barbara police each starred in made-for-TV movies: Model Behavior and The Luck of the Irish.",
		"answers": [
			"Psych",
			"10",
			"In",
			"series",
			"finale",
			"season",
			"3",
			"fake",
			"psychic",
			"Shawn",
			"Spencer",
			"challenged",
			"by",
			"Mr",
			"Yang",
			"serial",
			"killer",
			"based",
			"this",
			"famous",
			"Bay",
			"Area",
			"who",
			"was",
			"active",
			"in",
			"60's",
			"and",
			"70's",
			"California",
			"A",
			"movie",
			"released",
			"2007"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Psych[10] In the series finale of season 3 of Psych, fake psychic Shawn Spencer is challenged by Mr. Yang, a serial killer based on this famous Bay Area serial killer who was active in 60's and 70's California.  A movie based on this killer was released in 2007.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer these seemingly unrelated questions: [10] Starring Dulé Hill and James Roday, the main protagonist of this television show is obsessed with pineapples. The actors playing a pair of detectives for the Santa Barbara police each starred in made-for-TV movies: Model Behavior and The Luck of the Irish.",
		"answers": [
			"Psych",
			"10",
			"In",
			"series",
			"finale",
			"season",
			"3",
			"fake",
			"psychic",
			"Shawn",
			"Spencer",
			"challenged",
			"by",
			"Mr",
			"Yang",
			"serial",
			"killer",
			"based",
			"this",
			"famous",
			"Bay",
			"Area",
			"who",
			"was",
			"active",
			"in",
			"60's",
			"and",
			"70's",
			"California",
			"A",
			"movie",
			"released",
			"2007"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Man Your Man Could Smell Like [prompt \"Isaiah Mustafa;\" prompt answers such as \"Old Spice guy,\" though don't let teams know you can prompt them unless you do prompt this][10]  The Man Your Man Could Smell Like is in ads for this deodorant brand which produces Red Zone body spray. Its other campaigns include \"Experience is Everything.\"",
		"prompts": [
			"Isaiah",
			"Mustafa"
		],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In one parody of this figure, Grover of Sesame Street teaches children how to use the word \"on,\" and a seashell in his hand opens up to \"tickets to that thing you love,\" which melt into diamonds. For 10 points each: [10] Name this African-American figure first seen in a shower saying \"Look at your man, now back to me\" and later seen on a horse.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Man",
			"Your",
			"Could",
			"Smell",
			"Like"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Krishna[10] Arjuna was a member of this family, led by Yudhisthira during the Battle of Kurukshetra. This family fought against the Kauravas over the throne of Hastinapura.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 8 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This figure's birth occurred after his parents Vasudeva and Devaki were imprisoned. [10] Name this charioteer of Arjuna and blue-skinned avatar of Vishnu. He gave advice to Arjuna before the Battle of Kurukshetra in the Bhagavad Gita, and the Mahabharata culminates in his death.",
		"answers": [
			"Krishna",
			"10",
			"Arjuna",
			"was",
			"member",
			"this",
			"family",
			"led",
			"by",
			"Yudhisthira",
			"during",
			"Battle",
			"Kurukshetra",
			"This",
			"fought",
			"against",
			"Kauravas",
			"over",
			"throne",
			"Hastinapura"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Susano'o [or Takehaya Susanoo-no-Mikoto][10] Susanoo was born from the nose of this creator god during a purification ceremony, which occurred after this god returned from Yomi. He plunged a spear into the ocean with his wife, forming the islands of ancient Japan.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 3 | 18 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In Izumo Province, this figure turned Kushinada into a comb to hide in his hair. [10] Name this god of sea and storms who created five men from a necklace in a contest with his sister Amaterasu. This ruler of Yomi obtained the sword Kusanagi from the tail of the dragon Yamata no Orochi.",
		"answers": [
			"Susano'o",
			"Takehaya",
			"Susanoo-no-Mikoto",
			"10",
			"Susanoo",
			"was",
			"born",
			"from",
			"nose",
			"this",
			"creator",
			"god",
			"during",
			"purification",
			"ceremony",
			"which",
			"occurred",
			"after",
			"returned",
			"Yomi",
			"He",
			"plunged",
			"spear",
			"into",
			"ocean",
			"with",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"forming",
			"islands",
			"ancient",
			"Japan"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sekhmet [or Sachmis; or Sakhmet; or Sekhet; or Sakhet][10] Sekhmet's counterpart in Lower Egypt was this cat-headed goddess of warfare and protection, whose name translates to \"She of the Ointment Jar.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 8 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: During battle, this deity was said to drive a chariot in front of the pharaoh while firing flaming arrows. [10] Name this lion-headed Egyptian goddess who ravaged the earth, nearly destroying all of humanity. After drinking beer dyed with red ochre and pomegranate, she transformed into the cow-headed Hathor.",
		"answers": [
			"Sekhmet",
			"Sachmis",
			"Sakhmet",
			"Sekhet",
			"Sakhet",
			"10",
			"Sekhmet's",
			"counterpart",
			"in",
			"Lower",
			"Egypt",
			"was",
			"this",
			"cat-headed",
			"goddess",
			"warfare",
			"and",
			"protection",
			"whose",
			"name",
			"translates",
			"to",
			"She",
			"Ointment",
			"Jar"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Pegasus[10] Pegasus was famously ridden by this hero, who slew the Chimera before being stung by a gadfly and falling from the sky for his hubris.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2014 | 2 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Hippocrene spring on Mount Helicon was created by this figure. For 10 points each: [10] Name this winged-figure whose hooves created springs wherever they struck the ground.",
		"answers": [
			"Pegasus",
			"10",
			"was",
			"famously",
			"ridden",
			"by",
			"this",
			"hero",
			"who",
			"slew",
			"Chimera",
			"being",
			"stung",
			"gadfly",
			"and",
			"falling",
			"from",
			"sky",
			"for",
			"his",
			"hubris"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Odin (accept Woden, Wotan, or Wodan)[10] To gain the power of the runes, Odin used a spear to hang himself from this ash tree for nine days.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 3 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this chief deity of Norse myth, who gave up an eye to drink from the well of Mimir [MIH-mir].",
		"answers": [
			"Odin",
			"Woden",
			"Wotan",
			"Wodan",
			"10",
			"To",
			"gain",
			"power",
			"runes",
			"used",
			"spear",
			"to",
			"hang",
			"himself",
			"from",
			"this",
			"ash",
			"tree",
			"for",
			"nine",
			"days"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Telemachus[10] The ambush that awaited Telemachus [teh-leh-MAH-kus] was planned by suitors pursuing this queen, whose husband was absent for twenty years.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 3 | 10 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this youth, who was advised by Athena to take a different route home after visiting Nestor and Menelaus [meh-neh-LAY-us].",
		"answers": [
			"Telemachus",
			"10",
			"The",
			"ambush",
			"that",
			"awaited",
			"teh-leh-MAH-kus",
			"was",
			"planned",
			"by",
			"suitors",
			"pursuing",
			"this",
			"queen",
			"whose",
			"husband",
			"absent",
			"for",
			"twenty",
			"years"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Heracles (accept Hercules)[10] Zeus fathered Heracles by disguising himself as this king and sleeping with Alcmene [alk-MEE-nee] for three days and nights.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 4 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this hero who was undone by the poison of the Lernaean [LER-nay-un] hydra, which he killed as one of twelve labors ordered by his cousin Eurystheus [yoo-RIS-thee-us].",
		"answers": [
			"Heracles",
			"Hercules",
			"10",
			"Zeus",
			"fathered",
			"by",
			"disguising",
			"himself",
			"as",
			"this",
			"king",
			"and",
			"sleeping",
			"with",
			"Alcmene",
			"alk-MEE-nee",
			"for",
			"three",
			"days",
			"nights"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Theseus[10] After arriving in Athens to claim his rightful place, this wife of Aegeas and ex-wife of Jason convinced the king to try to poison Theseus. She also killed her sons Alcimenes [al-ki-MEE-nees] and Tisander.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 4 | 2 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this Athenian king and husband of Hippolyta [hih-poe-LIE-tah]. After this person forgot to change the flags following his conquering of the Labyrinth, his father Aegeas [ay-JEE-us] jumped into the sea.",
		"answers": [
			"Theseus",
			"10",
			"After",
			"arriving",
			"in",
			"Athens",
			"to",
			"claim",
			"his",
			"rightful",
			"place",
			"this",
			"wife",
			"Aegeas",
			"and",
			"ex-wife",
			"Jason",
			"convinced",
			"king",
			"try",
			"poison",
			"She",
			"also",
			"killed",
			"her",
			"sons",
			"Alcimenes",
			"al-ki-MEE-nees",
			"Tisander"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nuwa [or Nu Gua] [10] Nuwa is a deity from the mythology of this nation. In this mythology, the chief deity is the Jade Emperor.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In the Investiture of the Gods, this goddess' subordinates included the Nine-headed Pheasant. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this creator goddess who cut off the legs of a tortoise to repair the pillar of heaven. ",
		"answers": [
			"Nuwa",
			"Nu",
			"Gua",
			"10",
			"deity",
			"from",
			"mythology",
			"this",
			"nation",
			"In",
			"chief",
			"Jade",
			"Emperor"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "immortality[10] This centaur surrendered his immortality to free Prometheus. He mentored a number of heroes including Heracles and Achilles.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 17 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This quality was possessed by Pollux, but not Castor. For 10 points each: [10] Name this quality conferred by nectar and ambrosia. Possessed by the gods of Olympus, it makes the gods unchanging in their imperfections.",
		"answers": [
			"immortality",
			"10",
			"This",
			"centaur",
			"surrendered",
			"his",
			"to",
			"free",
			"Prometheus",
			"He",
			"mentored",
			"number",
			"heroes",
			"including",
			"Heracles",
			"and",
			"Achilles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Thor[10] Cursed with impotence during the Pandavas' exile, this Hindu hero from the Mahabharata crossdressed as Brihannala to teach music and dance. When the curse was lifted, he took up his bow to fight the Kauravas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 15 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Cross-dressing in mythology is quite popular! For 10 points each, name some figures who did so.  [10] This Norse god of thunder reluctantly dressed up as Freyja to marry the giant Thrym, who stole this god's hammer Mjolnir. ",
		"answers": [
			"Thor",
			"10",
			"Cursed",
			"with",
			"impotence",
			"during",
			"Pandavas'",
			"exile",
			"this",
			"Hindu",
			"hero",
			"from",
			"Mahabharata",
			"crossdressed",
			"as",
			"Brihannala",
			"to",
			"teach",
			"music",
			"and",
			"dance",
			"When",
			"curse",
			"was",
			"lifted",
			"he",
			"took",
			"up",
			"his",
			"bow",
			"fight",
			"Kauravas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cúchulainn (\"coo-HEL-en\") [or Cuhillin; or Setanta][10] Cúchulainn earned his name by killing one of these animals belonging to a blacksmith, though he later died after eating the meat of one of these. Cerberus is a three-headed one of these animals.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He is the son of Lugh and Deichtine. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Irish hero of the Ulster Cycle known for his berserker frenzy in battle. He was the sole defender in the Cattle Raid of Cooley.",
		"answers": [
			"Cúchulainn",
			"coo-HEL-en",
			"Cuhillin",
			"Setanta",
			"10",
			"earned",
			"his",
			"name",
			"by",
			"killing",
			"one",
			"these",
			"animals",
			"belonging",
			"to",
			"blacksmith",
			"though",
			"he",
			"later",
			"died",
			"after",
			"eating",
			"meat",
			"Cerberus",
			"three-headed"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "King Arthur Pendragon [prompt on Pendragon][10] Geoffrey of Monmouth wrote that this nephew of Arthur seduced Arthur's wife Guinevere, forcing Arthur to return from his wars against Rome. He was later portrayed as Arthur's son by his half-sister Morgause.",
		"prompts": [
			"Pendragon",
			"10",
			"Geoffrey",
			"Monmouth",
			"wrote",
			"that",
			"this",
			"nephew",
			"Arthur",
			"seduced",
			"Arthur's",
			"wife",
			"Guinevere",
			"forcing",
			"Arthur",
			"to",
			"return",
			"from",
			"his",
			"wars",
			"against",
			"Rome",
			"He",
			"was",
			"later",
			"portrayed",
			"as",
			"Arthur's",
			"son",
			"by",
			"his",
			"half-sister",
			"Morgause"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 04 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about a myth system written about by Geoffrey of Monmouth. For 10 points each: [10] Geoffrey of Monmouth's self-proclaimed \"histories\" mostly deal with this legendary king of England, who wielded Excalibur.",
		"answers": [
			"King",
			"Arthur",
			"Pendragon"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Psyche[10] Psyche's sisters convinced her to sneak a peek at her husband as he slept. Cupid didn't turn out to be hideous at all, but Psyche made this mistake, causing Cupid to wake up and flee.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 3 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: She was told that if she kept silent about her pregnancy, her child would be immortal. For 10 points each: [10] Name this woman prophesied to marry a hideous monster. She was assisted by ants, a talking reed, and an eagle in her quest to be reunited with her lover Cupid. ",
		"answers": [
			"Psyche",
			"10",
			"Psyche's",
			"sisters",
			"convinced",
			"her",
			"to",
			"sneak",
			"peek",
			"at",
			"husband",
			"as",
			"he",
			"slept",
			"Cupid",
			"didn't",
			"turn",
			"out",
			"be",
			"hideous",
			"all",
			"but",
			"made",
			"this",
			"mistake",
			"causing",
			"wake",
			"up",
			"and",
			"flee"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "beheading [or decapitation][10] Lancelot's encounter with the red-girdled knight is probably derived from an earlier depiction of this Arthurian knight's beheading game with the Green Knight.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 5 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In two instances, a game centered on this action included three faked strikes to test the recipient's resolve. For 10 points each: [10] Give this method of death, committed by Judith against Holofernes, and by Lancelot against a red-girdled knight in The High History of the Holy Grail.",
		"answers": [
			"beheading",
			"decapitation",
			"10",
			"Lancelot's",
			"encounter",
			"with",
			"red-girdled",
			"knight",
			"probably",
			"derived",
			"from",
			"an",
			"earlier",
			"depiction",
			"this",
			"Arthurian",
			"knight's",
			"game",
			"Green",
			"Knight"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "floods[10] In the Sumerian creation myth, this patron god of Eridu warns one human to build an ark to escape the oncoming flood. He is also the god of seawater, crafts, and mischief.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In Chinese mythology, Gun is first appointed to try to staunch the Great one of these with magically absorptive soil. For 10 points each: [10] Name these disasters common in mythology and religion, usually as divine retribution intended to start human civilization anew. In the book of Genesis, Noah saves his family and pairs of animals from one of these events.",
		"answers": [
			"floods",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Sumerian",
			"creation",
			"myth",
			"this",
			"patron",
			"god",
			"Eridu",
			"warns",
			"one",
			"human",
			"to",
			"build",
			"an",
			"ark",
			"escape",
			"oncoming",
			"flood",
			"He",
			"also",
			"seawater",
			"crafts",
			"and",
			"mischief"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Agamemnon[10] Calchas recommended interrogating Helenus, who revealed that the Achaeans would need the bones of this figure to take Troy. He was given an ivory shoulder blade after his father Tantalus cut him up for the gods.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about the prophecies of Calchas (\"KAHL-kahs\"), for 10 points each: [10] Calchas told this commander of Greek forces to sacrifice his daughter Iphigenia before setting sail for Troy. After the war, he was murdered by his wife Clytemnestra.",
		"answers": [
			"Agamemnon",
			"10",
			"Calchas",
			"recommended",
			"interrogating",
			"Helenus",
			"who",
			"revealed",
			"that",
			"Achaeans",
			"would",
			"need",
			"bones",
			"this",
			"figure",
			"to",
			"take",
			"Troy",
			"He",
			"was",
			"given",
			"an",
			"ivory",
			"shoulder",
			"blade",
			"after",
			"his",
			"father",
			"Tantalus",
			"cut",
			"him",
			"up",
			"for",
			"gods"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "breathing fire [or equivalents][10] Examples of these fire-breathing creatures in Greek myth include Ladon and Python. They're commonly depicted in Chinese myth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Brookwood Invitational Scholars Bowl |2013 | 1 | 2 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Konabos, some horses owned by Ares, possessed this ability. For 10 points each: [10] Name this ability. Bellerophon slew the Chimera because the beast attempted to use this ability while a lead spear was stuck down its throat.",
		"answers": [
			"breathing",
			"fire",
			"equivalents",
			"10",
			"Examples",
			"these",
			"fire-breathing",
			"creatures",
			"in",
			"Greek",
			"myth",
			"include",
			"Ladon",
			"and",
			"Python",
			"They're",
			"commonly",
			"depicted",
			"Chinese"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Jörmungandr [accept Midgard Serpent or World Serpent][10] That last battle will occur during this event, in which Fenrir will break free and eat the moon and the sun. It will also feature the destruction of the world by the armies of the fire-giant Surtr.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 10 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He surrounds the world and eats his own tail. For 10 points each: [10] Name this enormous monster who will kill and be killed by Thor in an epic battle.",
		"answers": [
			"Jörmungandr",
			"Midgard",
			"Serpent",
			"World",
			"10",
			"That",
			"last",
			"battle",
			"will",
			"occur",
			"during",
			"this",
			"event",
			"in",
			"which",
			"Fenrir",
			"break",
			"free",
			"and",
			"eat",
			"moon",
			"sun",
			"It",
			"also",
			"feature",
			"destruction",
			"world",
			"by",
			"armies",
			"fire-giant",
			"Surtr"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ares[10] This son of Myrrha and Cinyras was raised by Aphrodite, who fell in love with him. He died when a boar gored him, and Aphrodite patronized a yearly festival in his honor.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 21 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some lovers of Aphrodite, for 10 points each: [10] This god was trapped under a net with Aphrodite by her jealous husband Hephaestus. With her, he sired Phobos and Deimos, who accompanied him to war.",
		"answers": [
			"Ares",
			"10",
			"This",
			"son",
			"Myrrha",
			"and",
			"Cinyras",
			"was",
			"raised",
			"by",
			"Aphrodite",
			"who",
			"fell",
			"in",
			"love",
			"with",
			"him",
			"He",
			"died",
			"when",
			"boar",
			"gored",
			"patronized",
			"yearly",
			"festival",
			"his",
			"honor"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ra[10] Ra sent this terrible lioness to destroy humankind when they conspired against him. Before she could slaughter everyone, he stopped her by tricking her into drinking too much beer.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 10 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Mnevis bull symbolized this god in Heliopolis. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Egyptian Sun deity who slays Apophis in the form of a cat. He is often depicted with a falcon head.",
		"answers": [
			"Ra",
			"10",
			"sent",
			"this",
			"terrible",
			"lioness",
			"to",
			"destroy",
			"humankind",
			"when",
			"they",
			"conspired",
			"against",
			"him",
			"Before",
			"she",
			"could",
			"slaughter",
			"everyone",
			"he",
			"stopped",
			"her",
			"by",
			"tricking",
			"into",
			"drinking",
			"too",
			"much",
			"beer"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Argonauts[10] This former king of Thrace helped the Argonauts by revealing the secret to pass through the Sympleglades. His abuse of his foresight led to his blindness.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Members of this group included Hercules, the twins Castor and Pollux, and the only female, Atalanta. For 10 points each: [10] Name this group of adventurers that Jason took on his quest for the Golden Fleece.",
		"answers": [
			"Argonauts",
			"10",
			"This",
			"former",
			"king",
			"Thrace",
			"helped",
			"by",
			"revealing",
			"secret",
			"to",
			"pass",
			"through",
			"Sympleglades",
			"His",
			"abuse",
			"his",
			"foresight",
			"led",
			"blindness"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Furies [accept Erinyes, Eumenides, or Dirae][10] These Greek spirits of charm and beauty often appear nude in many sculptures. One of them, Thalia, shares her name with the Muse of comedy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer the following about mythological groups of three. [10] These flying hags persecute oath-breakers and murderers. They pursued Orestes until Athena personally stopped them.",
		"answers": [
			"Furies",
			"Erinyes",
			"Eumenides",
			"Dirae",
			"10",
			"These",
			"Greek",
			"spirits",
			"charm",
			"and",
			"beauty",
			"often",
			"appear",
			"nude",
			"in",
			"many",
			"sculptures",
			"One",
			"them",
			"Thalia",
			"shares",
			"her",
			"name",
			"with",
			"Muse",
			"comedy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hephaestus (do not accept or prompt on \"Vulcan\")[10] With Athena as his charioteer, this Greek soldier inflicted a wound upon Ares who was fighting alongside the Trojans. This man had ventured with Odysseus into Troy to retrieve the Palladium.",
		"prompts": [
			"Vulcan",
			"10",
			"With",
			"Athena",
			"as",
			"his",
			"charioteer",
			"this",
			"Greek",
			"soldier",
			"inflicted",
			"wound",
			"upon",
			"Ares",
			"who",
			"was",
			"fighting",
			"alongside",
			"Trojans",
			"This",
			"man",
			"had",
			"ventured",
			"with",
			"Odysseus",
			"into",
			"Troy",
			"to",
			"retrieve",
			"Palladium"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Though the god of war, it became a running joke in Greek mythology that Ares was actually a wimp. For 10 points each; [10] After learning that Ares was having an affair with his wife Aphrodite, this god of the smithy constructed a golden net and caught them in the act to the humor of the rest of the gods.",
		"answers": [
			"Hephaestus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "flood or Great Deluge[10] In Hindusim, this god's son Manu was the progenitor of mankind and had also survived a flood after being forewarned by the fish Shaphari. This god was the creator member of the Trimurti.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 15 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Noah survived one of these events using an ark. For 10 points each: [10] Name these events, one of which Deucalion and Pyrrha survived. Those two later recreated mankind using rocks.",
		"answers": [
			"flood",
			"Great",
			"Deluge",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Hindusim",
			"this",
			"god's",
			"son",
			"Manu",
			"was",
			"progenitor",
			"mankind",
			"and",
			"had",
			"also",
			"survived",
			"after",
			"being",
			"forewarned",
			"by",
			"fish",
			"Shaphari",
			"This",
			"god",
			"creator",
			"member",
			"Trimurti"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Jason[10] These hero twins were children of Leda. They were called the Dioscuri in Greek and the Gemini in Latin.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 20 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these members of the Argonauts: [10] This leader of the Argonauts began the expedition after being made to find the Golden Fleece by the usurping king Pelias.",
		"answers": [
			"Jason",
			"10",
			"These",
			"hero",
			"twins",
			"were",
			"children",
			"Leda",
			"They",
			"called",
			"Dioscuri",
			"in",
			"Greek",
			"and",
			"Gemini",
			"Latin"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Greek underworld (or Hades) [10] This ferryman escorted souls across the Styx into the underworld. A coin was usually buried with the dead to pay this son of Nyx and Erebus.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 6 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Its entrance is guarded by the three-headed dog Cerberus. For 10 points each:  [10] The Styx and Acheron rivers are located in what place in Greek mythology, where Persephone reigns as queen for nine months of the year? ",
		"answers": [
			"Greek",
			"underworld",
			"Hades",
			"10",
			"This",
			"ferryman",
			"escorted",
			"souls",
			"across",
			"Styx",
			"into",
			"A",
			"coin",
			"was",
			"usually",
			"buried",
			"with",
			"dead",
			"to",
			"pay",
			"this",
			"son",
			"Nyx",
			"and",
			"Erebus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cú Chulainn (prompt on \"Sétanta\")[10] Cú Chulainn was the son of this deity known as \"the long-handed\". After the Cattle Raid of Cooley this god healed Cú Culainn over a period of three days.",
		"prompts": [
			"Sétanta",
			"10",
			"Cú",
			"Chulainn",
			"was",
			"son",
			"this",
			"deity",
			"known",
			"as",
			"long-handed",
			"After",
			"Cattle",
			"Raid",
			"Cooley",
			"this",
			"god",
			"healed",
			"Cú",
			"Culainn",
			"over",
			"period",
			"three",
			"days"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 20 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This hero ensures that he would die standing upright by tying his intestines to a rock. For 10 points each: [10] Name this mythical warrior who was taught by Scathach and fights in the Cattle Raid of Cooley against Queen Medb. ",
		"answers": [
			"Cú",
			"Chulainn"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yggdrasil[10] This god hung himself upside-down from Yggdrasil for nine days and nine nights to be allowed to understand the language of runes. He also sacrificed an eye to drink from the Well of Mimir.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Well of Mimir is located under one of this entity's roots. For 10 points each: [10] Name this \"World Tree\" in Norse mythology. Its roots span Asgard and Hel.",
		"answers": [
			"Yggdrasil",
			"10",
			"This",
			"god",
			"hung",
			"himself",
			"upside-down",
			"from",
			"for",
			"nine",
			"days",
			"and",
			"nights",
			"to",
			"be",
			"allowed",
			"understand",
			"language",
			"runes",
			"He",
			"also",
			"sacrificed",
			"an",
			"eye",
			"drink",
			"Well",
			"Mimir"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ajax[10] Ajax the Greater is also sometimes named after this father of his who helped his friend Heracles in an earlier siege of Troy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 3 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One man with this name slaughtered a flock of sheep in a fit of madness for not winning Achilles's armor. For 10 points each: [10] Give this name of two men who fought in the Trojan War, one known as \"the Greater\" and the other as \"the Lesser.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Ajax",
			"10",
			"Greater",
			"also",
			"sometimes",
			"named",
			"after",
			"this",
			"father",
			"his",
			"who",
			"helped",
			"friend",
			"Heracles",
			"in",
			"an",
			"earlier",
			"siege",
			"Troy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cupid [10] Associated with love, music, dance, and motherhood this cow-headed Egyptian goddess is said to hold up the sky.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 20 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these gods and goddesses of love: [10] This Roman God of desire and affection is the son of Venus. He is often contrasted with the Greek Eros and usually is depicted as an archer with arrows of gold which cause people to fall in love. ",
		"answers": [
			"Cupid",
			"10",
			"Associated",
			"with",
			"love",
			"music",
			"dance",
			"and",
			"motherhood",
			"this",
			"cow-headed",
			"Egyptian",
			"goddess",
			"said",
			"to",
			"hold",
			"up",
			"sky"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Xibalba [shee-BAHL-bah][10] This pair of mythological siblings descended into Xibalba to play a ball game and defeat the Death Gods. They consist of Hunahpu [WAH-nuh-pwuh] and Xbalanque [shi-BAY-lan-kay].",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 5 | 5 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The name of this location is roughly translated as \"place of fear.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this underworld overseen by the Death Gods which included trials like the Bat House and the Razor House.",
		"answers": [
			"Xibalba",
			"shee-BAHL-bah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"pair",
			"mythological",
			"siblings",
			"descended",
			"into",
			"to",
			"play",
			"ball",
			"game",
			"and",
			"defeat",
			"Death",
			"Gods",
			"They",
			"consist",
			"Hunahpu",
			"WAH-nuh-pwuh",
			"Xbalanque",
			"shi-BAY-lan-kay"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vishnu[10] This god obtained a blue throat when he swallowed the poison produced during the churning. He is the father of Ganesh.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 12 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer the following about the churning of the ocean in Hindu mythology: [10] This Preserver member of the Trimurti took on the form of a turtle to act as a pivot for the mountain used in the churning. He is known for his many avatars. ",
		"answers": [
			"Vishnu",
			"10",
			"This",
			"god",
			"obtained",
			"blue",
			"throat",
			"when",
			"he",
			"swallowed",
			"poison",
			"produced",
			"during",
			"churning",
			"He",
			"father",
			"Ganesh"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Pegasus[10] This man tamed the winged-horse Pegasus using a golden bridle on the advice of Athena.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 4 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This creature helped fight against the Solymi and Amazons. For 10 points each: [10] Name this sibling of Chrysaor which was captured while it drank from the Pirene.",
		"answers": [
			"Pegasus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"tamed",
			"winged-horse",
			"using",
			"golden",
			"bridle",
			"advice",
			"Athena"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "giant (prompt on \"jotnar\")[10] Ymir was killed by Odin, Vili, and Ve, who were the first generation of this pantheon of gods. They wage a war with, and then combine with, the Vanir.",
		"prompts": [
			"jotnar",
			"10",
			"Ymir",
			"was",
			"killed",
			"by",
			"Odin",
			"Vili",
			"and",
			"Ve",
			"who",
			"were",
			"first",
			"generation",
			"this",
			"pantheon",
			"gods",
			"They",
			"wage",
			"war",
			"with",
			"and",
			"then",
			"combine",
			"with",
			"Vanir"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about the death of Ymir, which led to the creation of the world: [10] Ymir was the primordial first example of this type of creature in Norse mythology. The jotunn were the \"frost\" type of these large creatures.",
		"answers": [
			"giant"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "giant (prompt on \"jotnar\")[10] Ymir was killed by Odin, Vili, and Ve, who were the first generation of this pantheon of gods. They wage a war with, and then combine with, the Vanir.",
		"prompts": [
			"jotnar",
			"10",
			"Ymir",
			"was",
			"killed",
			"by",
			"Odin",
			"Vili",
			"and",
			"Ve",
			"who",
			"were",
			"first",
			"generation",
			"this",
			"pantheon",
			"gods",
			"They",
			"wage",
			"war",
			"with",
			"and",
			"then",
			"combine",
			"with",
			"Vanir"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about the death of Ymir, which led to the creation of the world: [10] Ymir was the primordial first example of this type of creature in Norse mythology. The jotunn were the \"frost\" type of these large creatures.",
		"answers": [
			"giant"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "centaurs[10] The immortal son of Cronus, this centaur served as the teacher of many heroes including Theseus.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: These creatures were born out of the union between Ixion and a thundercloud he believed to be Hera. For 10 points each: [10] Nessus was a famous one of what half-man, half-horse combinations?",
		"answers": [
			"centaurs",
			"10",
			"The",
			"immortal",
			"son",
			"Cronus",
			"this",
			"centaur",
			"served",
			"as",
			"teacher",
			"many",
			"heroes",
			"including",
			"Theseus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Krishna[10] Krishna is an avatar of this \"Preserver\" of the Hindu Trimurti. His other avatars include Rama and the fish Matsya, while his final avatar Kalki is yet to come.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this blue-skinned figure, a son of Devaki who served as the charioteer of Prince Arjuna. The dialogue between him and Arjuna makes up most of the Bhagavad Gita.",
		"answers": [
			"Krishna",
			"10",
			"an",
			"avatar",
			"this",
			"Preserver",
			"Hindu",
			"Trimurti",
			"His",
			"other",
			"avatars",
			"include",
			"Rama",
			"and",
			"fish",
			"Matsya",
			"while",
			"his",
			"final",
			"Kalki",
			"yet",
			"to",
			"come"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Thoth [or Djehuty; be lenient with vowels] [10] Thoth was sometimes described as the son of this bird-headed god, who drove the sun barge across the sky each day. He was sometimes merged with Amun or Atum.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 2 | 2 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  This god wrote a namesake book supposedly buried near Memphis that would give the reader the spells needed to control the gods. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Egyptian god with the long beak of an ibis. He took up residence on the moon and served as a divine scribe. ",
		"answers": [
			"Thoth",
			"Djehuty",
			"be",
			"lenient",
			"with",
			"vowels",
			"10",
			"was",
			"sometimes",
			"described",
			"as",
			"son",
			"this",
			"bird-headed",
			"god",
			"who",
			"drove",
			"sun",
			"barge",
			"across",
			"sky",
			"each",
			"day",
			"He",
			"merged",
			"Amun",
			"Atum"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "a boulder [or rock or stone] [10]  Sisyphus's crime was stopping this phenomenon from happening by tying up the god of it in his own chains. In the Iliad, the god of this phenomenon carries Sarpedon's corpse away along with his brother Sleep.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer these questions about the myth of Sisyphus, as in the actual Greek myth, for 10 points each. [10] Sisyphus's punishment is to push one of these objects uphill in Tartarus forever. ",
		"answers": [
			"a",
			"boulder",
			"rock",
			"stone",
			"10",
			"Sisyphus's",
			"crime",
			"was",
			"stopping",
			"this",
			"phenomenon",
			"from",
			"happening",
			"by",
			"tying",
			"up",
			"god",
			"in",
			"his",
			"own",
			"chains",
			"In",
			"Iliad",
			"carries",
			"Sarpedon's",
			"corpse",
			"away",
			"along",
			"with",
			"brother",
			"Sleep"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cadmus[10]  This man survived the great flood by hiding with his wife Pyrrha in a large chest. He and Pyrrha threw the \"bones of their mother,\" or stones, behind them to form the new human race.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 14 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Phoenician prince and brother of Europa was given dragon's teeth by Athena to plant in the ground. The oracle at Delphi told him to follow a cow, leading him to found Thebes.",
		"answers": [
			"Cadmus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"survived",
			"great",
			"flood",
			"by",
			"hiding",
			"with",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"Pyrrha",
			"in",
			"large",
			"chest",
			"He",
			"and",
			"threw",
			"bones",
			"their",
			"mother",
			"stones",
			"behind",
			"them",
			"to",
			"form",
			"new",
			"human",
			"race"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Thor[10]  This goddess and wife of Thor had golden hair, an allusion to wheat. Loki once cut her hair off, after which Thor threatened to break all of Loki's bones.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 8 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This son of Odin was served by Djalfi and wielded the hammer Mjolnir.",
		"answers": [
			"Thor",
			"10",
			"This",
			"goddess",
			"and",
			"wife",
			"had",
			"golden",
			"hair",
			"an",
			"allusion",
			"to",
			"wheat",
			"Loki",
			"once",
			"cut",
			"her",
			"off",
			"after",
			"which",
			"threatened",
			"break",
			"all",
			"Loki's",
			"bones"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sekhmet [accept Sakhmet, Sachmis, Sekhet, or Sakhet][10]  Sekhmet is the wife and sister of this green-skinned god, the patron of craftsmen. He is depicted in the linens of a mummy and carries a was sceptre with a djed and an ankh. In some myths, he thought the universe into existence.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This goddess has a lion's head and a woman's body. Ra created her to destroy mankind, but when she got out of hand, he tricked her into drinking seven thousand jars of beer, transforming her into her counterpart Hathor.",
		"answers": [
			"Sekhmet",
			"Sakhmet",
			"Sachmis",
			"Sekhet",
			"Sakhet",
			"10",
			"wife",
			"and",
			"sister",
			"this",
			"green-skinned",
			"god",
			"patron",
			"craftsmen",
			"He",
			"depicted",
			"in",
			"linens",
			"mummy",
			"carries",
			"was",
			"sceptre",
			"with",
			"djed",
			"an",
			"ankh",
			"In",
			"some",
			"myths",
			"he",
			"thought",
			"universe",
			"into",
			"existence"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Coyote[10]  This spider from African folklore tried to hoard all the world's knowledge in a pot, but dropped it out of annoyance at being bested by his son.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 8 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Native American trickster god stole fire from the gods by dancing around it with reeds on his head, and running away before the gods stopped laughing.",
		"answers": [
			"Coyote",
			"10",
			"This",
			"spider",
			"from",
			"African",
			"folklore",
			"tried",
			"to",
			"hoard",
			"all",
			"world's",
			"knowledge",
			"in",
			"pot",
			"but",
			"dropped",
			"out",
			"annoyance",
			"at",
			"being",
			"bested",
			"by",
			"his",
			"son"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hades or Plouton [do not accept \"Pluto\"][10]  This Norse goddess is the daughter of Loki, and the world she rules bears her name. She is often described as half-flesh and half-black or rot, and with a generally melancholy air.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 14 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Greek god of the dead is also known as \"The Rich One,\" and famously captured Demeter's daughter, Persephone, to be his wife. Hercules asked this god for his dog, Cerberus.",
		"answers": [
			"Hades",
			"Plouton"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Andromache[10]  This husband of Andromache led the Trojans against the Greeks. He dueled Ajax and killed Patroclus before he was chased around the walls of Troy, killed, and had his body mistreated.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this mother of Astyanax and wife of the greatest Trojan hero. She was taken as Neoptolemus's concubine during the Trojan War but later married Helenus.",
		"answers": [
			"Andromache",
			"10",
			"This",
			"husband",
			"led",
			"Trojans",
			"against",
			"Greeks",
			"He",
			"dueled",
			"Ajax",
			"and",
			"killed",
			"Patroclus",
			"he",
			"was",
			"chased",
			"around",
			"walls",
			"Troy",
			"had",
			"his",
			"body",
			"mistreated"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bellerophon[10]  Bellerophon used a golden bridle to tame this magical winged horse with whom he killed the Chimera. he and his brother Chrysaor sprung from the decapitated corpse of Medusa.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 11 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this mythological hero who slew his most famous enemy with a lump of lead attached to a spear. This man lived on the Plains of Aleion after being blinded and crippled by a gadfly sent by Zeus.",
		"answers": [
			"Bellerophon",
			"10",
			"used",
			"golden",
			"bridle",
			"to",
			"tame",
			"this",
			"magical",
			"winged",
			"horse",
			"with",
			"whom",
			"he",
			"killed",
			"Chimera",
			"and",
			"his",
			"brother",
			"Chrysaor",
			"sprung",
			"from",
			"decapitated",
			"corpse",
			"Medusa"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ymir [accept Aurgelmir, Brimir, or Blainn][10]  When Ymir got too huge and powerful, Vili, Ve, and this god killed him. He is the husband of Frigg and ruler of the Aesir.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 19 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This giant was the first being, created when the fire of Muspelheim and the ice of Niflheim formed a water droplet. A race of frost giants descended from him.",
		"answers": [
			"Ymir",
			"Aurgelmir",
			"Brimir",
			"Blainn",
			"10",
			"When",
			"got",
			"too",
			"huge",
			"and",
			"powerful",
			"Vili",
			"Ve",
			"this",
			"god",
			"killed",
			"him",
			"He",
			"husband",
			"Frigg",
			"ruler",
			"Aesir"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tiamat[10]  This god used a whole slew of weapons, including a giant net, a flood-storm, and a whole bunch of winds, to kill Tiamat. After he succeeded, he was made the chief Babylonian god and was given 50 names.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round09.docx | 10 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this massive dragon in Babylonian myth, the primordial personification of chaos and the ocean. After her defeat, her body was split in two and used to form the world.",
		"answers": [
			"Tiamat",
			"10",
			"This",
			"god",
			"used",
			"whole",
			"slew",
			"weapons",
			"including",
			"giant",
			"net",
			"flood-storm",
			"and",
			"bunch",
			"winds",
			"to",
			"kill",
			"After",
			"he",
			"succeeded",
			"was",
			"made",
			"chief",
			"Babylonian",
			"given",
			"50",
			"names"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Priam[10]  This princess was the daughter of Priam and Hecuba. She had the gift of foresight but was cursed by Apollo so that nobody would listen to her predictions.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man was the king of Troy at the time of the Iliad. This father of Hector was killed by Achilles's son.",
		"answers": [
			"Priam",
			"10",
			"This",
			"princess",
			"was",
			"daughter",
			"and",
			"Hecuba",
			"She",
			"had",
			"gift",
			"foresight",
			"but",
			"cursed",
			"by",
			"Apollo",
			"so",
			"that",
			"nobody",
			"would",
			"listen",
			"to",
			"her",
			"predictions"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Galatea[10]  This extremely ugly satyr was the god of nature. His flute was made from reeds, which the nymph Syrinx changed into after he chased her.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 13 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Pygmalion fell in love with this creation of his, a sculpture of a woman. He prayed to Venus, who turned this woman from ivory to flesh.",
		"answers": [
			"Galatea",
			"10",
			"This",
			"extremely",
			"ugly",
			"satyr",
			"was",
			"god",
			"nature",
			"His",
			"flute",
			"made",
			"from",
			"reeds",
			"which",
			"nymph",
			"Syrinx",
			"changed",
			"into",
			"after",
			"he",
			"chased",
			"her"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rama[10]  Rama's main enemy was this demon king of Lanka who had ten heads and performed immense penances to Brahma and Shiva to gain power. He stored the nectar of immortality in his navel, making him effectively invincible.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 5 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this self-exiled king of Kosala, a man with blue skin who wielded the bow. He is featured in a namesake epic.",
		"answers": [
			"Rama",
			"10",
			"Rama's",
			"main",
			"enemy",
			"was",
			"this",
			"demon",
			"king",
			"Lanka",
			"who",
			"had",
			"ten",
			"heads",
			"and",
			"performed",
			"immense",
			"penances",
			"to",
			"Brahma",
			"Shiva",
			"gain",
			"power",
			"He",
			"stored",
			"nectar",
			"immortality",
			"in",
			"his",
			"navel",
			"making",
			"him",
			"effectively",
			"invincible"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mayans[10]  Translated by Francisco Ximenez, the title of this four-part work means \"Book of the People.\" It recounts three attempts at creating humans, and the tale of the first four men, their wives, and the First Dawn.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 11 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  These Mesomaerican people believed the god Itzamna brought them writing and the calendar system, which includes the 260-day Tzolkin count and the Long Count, which ended in December 2012.",
		"answers": [
			"Mayans",
			"10",
			"Translated",
			"by",
			"Francisco",
			"Ximenez",
			"title",
			"this",
			"four-part",
			"work",
			"means",
			"Book",
			"People",
			"It",
			"recounts",
			"three",
			"attempts",
			"at",
			"creating",
			"humans",
			"and",
			"tale",
			"first",
			"four",
			"men",
			"their",
			"wives",
			"First",
			"Dawn"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Krishna[10]  Krishna is an avatar of this \"Preserver\" of the Hindu Trimurti. His other avatars include Rama and the fish Matsya, while his final avatar Kalki is yet to come.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this blue-skinned figure, a son of Devaki who served as the charioteer of Prince Arjuna. The dialogue between him and Arjuna makes up most of the Bhagavad Gita.",
		"answers": [
			"Krishna",
			"10",
			"an",
			"avatar",
			"this",
			"Preserver",
			"Hindu",
			"Trimurti",
			"His",
			"other",
			"avatars",
			"include",
			"Rama",
			"and",
			"fish",
			"Matsya",
			"while",
			"his",
			"final",
			"Kalki",
			"yet",
			"to",
			"come"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gigantomachy (accept equivalents like Giant War)[10]  The Giants were sons of this personification of the Earth. With Ouranos, she was the mother of the Titans, Hekatonkheires, and Cyclopes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this rebellion against the Olympian gods, which was quelled with the help of Heracles. Some participants in it could not be killed unless they were taken out of their homeland of Pallene.",
		"answers": [
			"Gigantomachy",
			"equivalents",
			"Giant",
			"War",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Giants",
			"were",
			"sons",
			"this",
			"personification",
			"Earth",
			"With",
			"Ouranos",
			"she",
			"was",
			"mother",
			"Titans",
			"Hekatonkheires",
			"and",
			"Cyclopes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Odin (accept Wotan or Woden)[10]  With his brothers Vili and Ve, Odin killed this primordial giant to build the world. He was formed in Ginnungagap by the union of fire and ice.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 13 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this owner of the ravens Hugin and Munin who was the chief Norse deity and father of the Aesir.",
		"answers": [
			"Odin",
			"Wotan",
			"Woden",
			"10",
			"With",
			"his",
			"brothers",
			"Vili",
			"and",
			"Ve",
			"killed",
			"this",
			"primordial",
			"giant",
			"to",
			"build",
			"world",
			"He",
			"was",
			"formed",
			"in",
			"Ginnungagap",
			"by",
			"union",
			"fire",
			"ice"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ahuramazda (or Ohrmazd)[10]  Ahuramazda and Angra Mainyu are the two central gods of this Persian religion, the chief text of which is the Avesta.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 5 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this \"good god\" who is rivals with Angra Mainyu in a dualistic Persian religion.",
		"answers": [
			"Ahuramazda",
			"Ohrmazd",
			"10",
			"and",
			"Angra",
			"Mainyu",
			"are",
			"two",
			"central",
			"gods",
			"this",
			"Persian",
			"religion",
			"chief",
			"text",
			"which",
			"Avesta"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ixion[10]  Nephele married King Athamas, but he later got rid of her in favor of Ino, a daughter of this man. This figure was the husband  of Harmonia and founder of Thebes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 18 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this king of the Lapiths and father of Pirithous, who was later chained to a fiery wheel in Hades because he could not contain his lust for Hera. With the cloud nymph Nephele, he was the father of the Centaurs.",
		"answers": [
			"Ixion",
			"10",
			"Nephele",
			"married",
			"King",
			"Athamas",
			"but",
			"he",
			"later",
			"got",
			"rid",
			"her",
			"in",
			"favor",
			"Ino",
			"daughter",
			"this",
			"man",
			"This",
			"figure",
			"was",
			"husband",
			"Harmonia",
			"and",
			"founder",
			"Thebes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Beowulf[10]  This kami of storms and the sea slew the dragon Orochi and pulled the sword Kusanagi from its tail. He was born with his siblings, the goddess of the Sun and the god of the Moon,  from Izanagi's face.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This owner of the sword Hrunting and hero of a namesake Anglo-Saxon epic discovered that the weapon failed to work against Grendel's Mother, forcing him to discard it.",
		"answers": [
			"Beowulf",
			"10",
			"This",
			"kami",
			"storms",
			"and",
			"sea",
			"slew",
			"dragon",
			"Orochi",
			"pulled",
			"sword",
			"Kusanagi",
			"from",
			"its",
			"tail",
			"He",
			"was",
			"born",
			"with",
			"his",
			"siblings",
			"goddess",
			"Sun",
			"god",
			"Moon",
			"Izanagi's",
			"face"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Romulus[10]  Romulus ordered a kidnapping of this tribe's women to provide wives for the inhabitants of Rome. In retaliation, their king Titus Tatius attacked Rome, only to be stopped when the women threw themselves before the troops.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 4 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man founded Rome with his brother Remus, but later killed him for criticizing the height of the city's walls.",
		"answers": [
			"Romulus",
			"10",
			"ordered",
			"kidnapping",
			"this",
			"tribe's",
			"women",
			"to",
			"provide",
			"wives",
			"for",
			"inhabitants",
			"Rome",
			"In",
			"retaliation",
			"their",
			"king",
			"Titus",
			"Tatius",
			"attacked",
			"only",
			"be",
			"stopped",
			"when",
			"threw",
			"themselves",
			"troops"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cattle Raid of Cooley (or Tain Bo Cuailnge; accept any answer indicating a theft of cattle from Cooley)[10]  The Cattle Raid of Cooley is recorded in the Ulster Cycle of this country's mythology. Famous figures in this country's mythology include Deirdre of the Sorrows and Finn MacCool.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 3 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this event in which the armies of Queen Medb attacked Ulster in an attempt to steal a valuable bull.",
		"answers": [
			"Cattle",
			"Raid",
			"Cooley",
			"Tain",
			"Bo",
			"Cuailnge",
			"answer",
			"indicating",
			"theft",
			"cattle",
			"from",
			"10",
			"The",
			"recorded",
			"in",
			"Ulster",
			"Cycle",
			"this",
			"country's",
			"mythology",
			"Famous",
			"figures",
			"include",
			"Deirdre",
			"Sorrows",
			"and",
			"Finn",
			"MacCool"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "oracles (do not accept or prompt on \"prophets\")[10]  Apollo established the Oracle of Delphi after killing this serpent, which had been pursuing his mother Leto. The predecessor to the Olympic Games were held to commemorate the killing of this creature.",
		"prompts": [
			"prophets",
			"10",
			"Apollo",
			"established",
			"Oracle",
			"Delphi",
			"after",
			"killing",
			"this",
			"serpent",
			"which",
			"had",
			"been",
			"pursuing",
			"his",
			"mother",
			"Leto",
			"The",
			"predecessor",
			"to",
			"Olympic",
			"Games",
			"were",
			"held",
			"to",
			"commemorate",
			"killing",
			"this",
			"creature"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name these places or people through which the gods communicated when consulted. The most famous example of these was the one at Delphi dedicated to Apollo.",
		"answers": [
			"oracles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Huitzilopochtli [accept Uitzilopochtli, prompt on some combination of \"Hummingbird\" and \"left\"][10]  Huitzilopochtli, whose Nahuatl name meant \"hummingbird on the left\", was the war god of these Mesoamerican people. Ometeotl was their creator god, and Tezcatlipoca served as their sorcerer.",
		"prompts": [
			"some",
			"combination",
			"Hummingbird",
			"and",
			"left",
			"10",
			"Huitzilopochtli",
			"whose",
			"Nahuatl",
			"name",
			"meant",
			"hummingbird",
			"left",
			"was",
			"war",
			"god",
			"these",
			"Mesoamerican",
			"people",
			"Ometeotl",
			"was",
			"their",
			"creator",
			"god",
			"and",
			"Tezcatlipoca",
			"served",
			"as",
			"their",
			"sorcerer"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this hummingbird god of war who required human sacrifices every 52 years. His mother was impregnated by a ball of feathers, leading to his birth.",
		"answers": [
			"Huitzilopochtli",
			"Uitzilopochtli"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Troy (or Ilium, or Ilion, or Ilios)[10]  This king ruled Troy at the time of the Trojan War and was the father of Hector. He was killed by Neoptolemus during the sack of Troy, after which his wife Hecuba was sold as a slave to Odysseus.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 5 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this city in Asia Minor that was conquered and destroyed by the Greeks in a war chronicled by a Homeric epic. The army of this city was led by Hector.",
		"answers": [
			"Troy",
			"Ilium",
			"Ilion",
			"Ilios",
			"10",
			"This",
			"king",
			"ruled",
			"at",
			"time",
			"Trojan",
			"War",
			"and",
			"was",
			"father",
			"Hector",
			"He",
			"killed",
			"by",
			"Neoptolemus",
			"during",
			"sack",
			"after",
			"which",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"Hecuba",
			"sold",
			"as",
			"slave",
			"to",
			"Odysseus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Coltrane[10]  Coltrane played the tenor variety of this instrument, the alto and soprano types of which were played by Charlie Parker and Kenny G.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this jazz musician, who also recorded Giant Steps and My Favorite Things. Ira Gitler famously described his music as \"sheets of sound.\"",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Coltrane",
			"10",
			"played",
			"tenor",
			"variety",
			"this",
			"instrument",
			"alto",
			"and",
			"soprano",
			"types",
			"which",
			"were",
			"by",
			"Charlie",
			"Parker",
			"Kenny",
			"G"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Geb (accept Gebeb, Keb, or Kebeb)[10]  Due to a restriction put in place by Ra, Geb's wife Nut could not give birth on all 360 days of the year, so this divine scribe and god of wisdom gambled with Khonsu for 5 extra days in the year during which Nut could give birth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 16 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this god of the earth and father of Osiris, Set, Isis, and Nepthys. This son of Shu and Tefnut married his sky-goddess sister.",
		"answers": [
			"Geb",
			"Gebeb",
			"Keb",
			"Kebeb",
			"10",
			"Due",
			"to",
			"restriction",
			"put",
			"in",
			"place",
			"by",
			"Ra",
			"Geb's",
			"wife",
			"Nut",
			"could"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Aethiopia[10]  This man's son was the Aethiopian prince Memnon. Priam bribed this lover of Eos with a golden grapevine, and he turned into a cicada after receiving immortality without eternal youth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 3 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this nebulously defined African region where the Olympians would often go and feast. It shares its name with a country whose former ruler, Haile Selassie, is venerated by Rastafarians.",
		"answers": [
			"Aethiopia",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man's",
			"son",
			"was",
			"Aethiopian",
			"prince",
			"Memnon",
			"Priam",
			"bribed",
			"this",
			"lover",
			"Eos",
			"with",
			"golden",
			"grapevine",
			"and",
			"he",
			"turned",
			"into",
			"cicada",
			"after",
			"receiving",
			"immortality",
			"without",
			"eternal",
			"youth"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "spiders[10]  This Native American trickster god is the brother of Wolf and created humanity by kicking a ball of dirt.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  One of these animals, the African trickster god Anansi, managed to get ahold of all the stories in the world. In Greek mythology, Arachne was turned into one of these after losing a weaving contest.",
		"answers": [
			"spiders",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Native",
			"American",
			"trickster",
			"god",
			"brother",
			"Wolf",
			"and",
			"created",
			"humanity",
			"by",
			"kicking",
			"ball",
			"dirt"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Theseus[10]  Theseus killed the Minotaur with the help of this daughter of Minos, who gave him some thread so that he could find a way out of the Labyrinth. However, Theseus abandoned her on Naxos while on the way back to Athens.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 17 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this son of Aegeus, a Greek hero who slew the Minotaur.",
		"answers": [
			"Theseus",
			"10",
			"killed"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "valkyries[10]  Actually, valkyries only carry half the valiant dead to Valhalla. The other half are selected by this Norse goddess of beauty and sent to a hall named Folkvangr.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 22 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Norse shieldmaidens who carried the valiant dead away to Valhalla.",
		"answers": [
			"valkyries",
			"10",
			"Actually",
			"only",
			"carry",
			"half",
			"valiant",
			"dead",
			"to",
			"Valhalla",
			"The",
			"other",
			"are",
			"selected",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Norse",
			"goddess",
			"beauty",
			"and",
			"sent",
			"hall",
			"named",
			"Folkvangr"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ra (or Atum-Ra, or Amun-Ra, or Ra-Horakhty; accept Re in place of \"Ra\"; prompt on Atum, Amun, or Horakhty)[10]  Amenhotep IV changed his name to honor this deity, the worship of whom replaced that of Ra and other traditional Egyptian gods. This god represented the solar disk.",
		"prompts": [
			"Atum",
			"Amun",
			"Horakhty",
			"10",
			"Amenhotep",
			"IV",
			"changed",
			"his",
			"name",
			"to",
			"honor",
			"this",
			"deity",
			"worship",
			"whom",
			"replaced",
			"that",
			"Ra",
			"and",
			"other",
			"traditional",
			"Egyptian",
			"gods",
			"This",
			"god",
			"represented",
			"solar",
			"disk"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 17 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Egyptian god of the sun was the grandfather of Osiris and Isis.",
		"answers": [
			"Ra",
			"Atum-Ra",
			"Amun-Ra",
			"Ra-Horakhty",
			"Re",
			"in",
			"place"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Epimetheus[10]  Unfortunately, Epimetheus didn't listen and accepted this woman as a bride. As a wedding present, she received a box that later released various evils and illnesses to humanity when she opened it.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 10 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this son of Iapetus whose name means \"afterthought\". He was warned by his wiser brother to never accept any gift from Zeus.",
		"answers": [
			"Epimetheus",
			"10",
			"Unfortunately",
			"didn't",
			"listen",
			"and",
			"accepted",
			"this",
			"woman",
			"as",
			"bride",
			"As",
			"wedding",
			"present",
			"she",
			"received",
			"box",
			"that",
			"later",
			"released",
			"various",
			"evils",
			"illnesses",
			"to",
			"humanity",
			"when",
			"opened"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigurd [or Siegfried; or Sifrid][10] Fafnir the dragon sat on a hoard of this substance, which King Midas turned things into with his accursed touch.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: After tasting the heart of the dragon Fafnir, this man learned to understand the language of birds. For 10 points  each: [10] Name this Germanic hero, a son of Sigmund who wrote through a circle of flames to rescue the maiden  Brynhild.",
		"answers": [
			"Sigurd",
			"Siegfried",
			"Sifrid",
			"10",
			"Fafnir",
			"dragon",
			"sat",
			"hoard",
			"this",
			"substance",
			"which",
			"King",
			"Midas",
			"turned",
			"things",
			"into",
			"with",
			"his",
			"accursed",
			"touch"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigurd [or Siegfried; or Sifrid][10] Fafnir the dragon sat on a hoard of this substance, which King Midas turned things into with his accursed touch.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: After tasting the heart of the dragon Fafnir, this man learned to understand the language of birds. For 10 points  each: [10] Name this Germanic hero, a son of Sigmund who wrote through a circle of flames to rescue the maiden  Brynhild.",
		"answers": [
			"Sigurd",
			"Siegfried",
			"Sifrid",
			"10",
			"Fafnir",
			"dragon",
			"sat",
			"hoard",
			"this",
			"substance",
			"which",
			"King",
			"Midas",
			"turned",
			"things",
			"into",
			"with",
			"his",
			"accursed",
			"touch"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lancelot[10] Lancelot was raised by this woman after the death of his father. In some stories, she trapped the smitten Merlin  in a tree after learning magic from him.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 6 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about King Arthur's Court, for 10 points each: [10] This Knight conducted an affair with Guinevere, but was banished after he sired Galahad with Elaine.",
		"answers": [
			"Lancelot",
			"10",
			"was",
			"raised",
			"by",
			"this",
			"woman",
			"after",
			"death",
			"his",
			"father",
			"In",
			"some",
			"stories",
			"she",
			"trapped",
			"smitten",
			"Merlin",
			"in",
			"tree",
			"learning",
			"magic",
			"from",
			"him"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Hesperides[10] This Titan was condemned to hold up the sky after the Titanomachy. Heracles had him collect golden apples  from the Hesperides, then tricked him into taking back his burden.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 19. [10] These nymphs of the evening tended their namesake garden and guarded the immortality-giving apples of a tree  belonging to Hera.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Hesperides",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Titan",
			"was",
			"condemned",
			"to",
			"hold",
			"up",
			"sky",
			"after",
			"Titanomachy",
			"Heracles",
			"had",
			"him",
			"collect",
			"golden",
			"apples",
			"from",
			"then",
			"tricked",
			"into",
			"taking",
			"back",
			"his",
			"burden"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vainamoinen[10] Vainamoinen sails away after Marjotta's son chides him for his sins at the end of this epic poem. Other  episodes involve Ilmarinen's Bride of Gold and Kullervo's misfortune.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 14 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Aino drowned herself rather than marry this bard. For 10 points each: [10] Name this rival of Joukahanien who tortured the Luotes out of Antero Vipunen. He also tried to woo the  Maiden of the North and tricked Ilmarinen into crafting the Sampo.",
		"answers": [
			"Vainamoinen",
			"10",
			"sails",
			"away",
			"after",
			"Marjotta's",
			"son",
			"chides",
			"him",
			"for",
			"his",
			"sins",
			"at",
			"end",
			"this",
			"epic",
			"poem",
			"Other",
			"episodes",
			"involve",
			"Ilmarinen's",
			"Bride",
			"Gold",
			"and",
			"Kullervo's",
			"misfortune"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ireland [accept Eire][10] This Irish hero fought the Fomorians in his travels, but is best known for going berserk and crushing the armies of Connacht under Queen Maeve during the Cattle Raid of Cooley.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This place was once invaded by the Fomorians, led by giants like Balor of the Evil Eye, as recorded in the Book of Invasions. For 10 points each: [10] Name this place where races like the Fir Bolg were displaced by the Tuatha de Danann. In real life this island was invaded by Oliver Cromwell, leading to the Siege of Drogheda.",
		"answers": [
			"Ireland",
			"Eire",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Irish",
			"hero",
			"fought",
			"Fomorians",
			"in",
			"his",
			"travels",
			"but",
			"best",
			"known",
			"for",
			"going",
			"berserk",
			"and",
			"crushing",
			"armies",
			"Connacht",
			"under",
			"Queen",
			"Maeve",
			"during",
			"Cattle",
			"Raid",
			"Cooley"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Arjuna[10] The Pandavas fought against their cousins, members of this lineage, led by patriarch Dhritarashtra and his son Duryodhana.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 5 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Agni gave a gift to this warrior, which he then used to slay his foe and half-brother, Karna. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this third of the Pandavas, sired by Indra, whose chariot was driven by Krishna at the Battle of Kurukshetra.",
		"answers": [
			"Arjuna",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Pandavas",
			"fought",
			"against",
			"their",
			"cousins",
			"members",
			"this",
			"lineage",
			"led",
			"by",
			"patriarch",
			"Dhritarashtra",
			"and",
			"his",
			"son",
			"Duryodhana"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Huitzilopochtli[10] Huitzilopochtli was the patron deity of this place, the capital city of the Nahua people, perhaps better known as the Aztecs.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 14 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This deity, son of Coatlicue, led the Nahua people out of Aztlan and commanded them never to return. For 10 points each: [10]  Identify this deity of war and the sun, whose name translates as \"blue hummingbird of the left.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Huitzilopochtli",
			"10",
			"was",
			"patron",
			"deity",
			"this",
			"place",
			"capital",
			"city",
			"Nahua",
			"people",
			"perhaps",
			"better",
			"known",
			"as",
			"Aztecs"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "On Liberty[10] On Liberty was written by this British philosopher who also wrote Utilitarianism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 3 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this work, the author justifies despotism over barbarians to prepare them for democratic rule. [10] Name this 1859 essay in which the author argues for freedom of speech and other forms of the title concept and argues that the only reason the title concept should be limited is to prevent harm to others.",
		"answers": [
			"On",
			"Liberty",
			"10",
			"was",
			"written",
			"by",
			"this",
			"British",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"also",
			"wrote",
			"Utilitarianism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "games[10] In game theory, a dominant strategy for a player is one which is this type of response to all of his opponent's strategies.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 17 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: A zero-sum one of these occurs when the gains of one competitor are negated by the losses of others. [10] Name these hypothetical situations created by a namesake study of decision making. In these constructs, exemplified by the prisoner's dilemma, rational beings cooperate and compete with each other.",
		"answers": [
			"games",
			"10",
			"In",
			"game",
			"theory",
			"dominant",
			"strategy",
			"for",
			"player",
			"one",
			"which",
			"this",
			"type",
			"response",
			"to",
			"all",
			"his",
			"opponent's",
			"strategies"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "cruel and unusual punishment [accept equivalents like \"cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment\"; do not accept specific instances like \"torture\" or \"enhanced interrogation\"][10] In Furman v. Georgia, the Supreme Court declared that inconsistencies in this form of punishment make this cruel and unusual. In the United States, it is primarily conducted through lethal injection.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 3 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In Trop v. Dulles, Chief Justice Earl Warren wrote that this concept \"must draw its meaning from the evolving standards of decency that mark the progress of a maturing society.\" [10] Name this concept prohibited in the Eighth Amendment of the United States Constitution. This phrase may have first been used to describe the sentence of Titus Oates after the uncovering of the Popish Plot.",
		"answers": [
			"cruel",
			"and",
			"unusual",
			"punishment",
			"equivalents",
			"inhuman",
			"degrading",
			"treatment"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "suicide[10] Suicide was analyzed in a case study by this French sociologist, who helped develop sociology as a field with his The Rules of Sociological Method.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 9 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Albert Camus described it as the only philosophical question. [10] Name this act of killing oneself. One man studying it noted its increased prevalence among Protestant communities, as well as its decreased prevalence during times of war.",
		"answers": [
			"suicide",
			"10",
			"Suicide",
			"was",
			"analyzed",
			"in",
			"case",
			"study",
			"by",
			"this",
			"French",
			"sociologist",
			"who",
			"helped",
			"develop",
			"sociology",
			"as",
			"field",
			"with",
			"his",
			"The",
			"Rules",
			"Sociological",
			"Method"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Invisible Hand\"[10] This economist posited the idea of the \"invisible hand\" in his works The Theory of Moral Sentiments and The Wealth of Nations.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2014 | 2 | 1 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This concept argues that individual self-interest in the economy benefits society overall. For 10 points each: [10] Name this metaphor used by a Scottish economist to describe the self-regulation of a free market.",
		"answers": [
			"Invisible",
			"Hand",
			"10",
			"This",
			"economist",
			"posited",
			"idea",
			"invisible",
			"hand",
			"in",
			"his",
			"works",
			"The",
			"Theory",
			"Moral",
			"Sentiments",
			"and",
			"Wealth",
			"Nations"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "emotions[10] This first theory proposed to explain emotions describes how the mind receives the bodily response first and experiences emotion afterwards.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 8 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: According to one theory, the mind uses both the situation and the physical response to a stimulus to interpret these phenomena. For 10 points each:  [10] Identify these phenomena explained by the Schachter-Singer and Cannon-Bard theories, which include happiness, sadness, and fear. ",
		"answers": [
			"emotions",
			"10",
			"This",
			"first",
			"theory",
			"proposed",
			"to",
			"explain",
			"describes",
			"how",
			"mind",
			"receives",
			"bodily",
			"response",
			"and",
			"experiences",
			"emotion",
			"afterwards"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Art of War[10] The uncertainty of war is also described as part of a \"fascinating trinity\" in On War, a text on early 19th-century European warfare by this Prussian officer who served during the Napoleonic Wars.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer these questions about learning proper fighting strategy. [10] Name this book by Sun Tzu on tactics, strategy, and military organization. It contains sections on martial arts and terrain, and characterizes war as an information game involving deception and uncertainty. ",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Art",
			"War",
			"10",
			"uncertainty",
			"war",
			"also",
			"described",
			"as",
			"part",
			"fascinating",
			"trinity",
			"in",
			"On",
			"text",
			"early",
			"19th-century",
			"European",
			"warfare",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Prussian",
			"officer",
			"who",
			"served",
			"during",
			"Napoleonic",
			"Wars"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Emile Durkheim[10] This anxiety disorder is often comorbid with suicidality. Its symptoms include flashbacks, irritability, and hypervigilance. It occurs frequently among military personnel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 18 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name the following about the study of suicide.  [10] The first sociological study of suicide was conducted by this French author of Rules of the Sociological Method. He studied differences in suicide rates between Catholic and Protestant communities.",
		"answers": [
			"Emile",
			"Durkheim",
			"10",
			"This",
			"anxiety",
			"disorder",
			"often",
			"comorbid",
			"with",
			"suicidality",
			"Its",
			"symptoms",
			"include",
			"flashbacks",
			"irritability",
			"and",
			"hypervigilance",
			"It",
			"occurs",
			"frequently",
			"among",
			"military",
			"personnel"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gross domestic product or GDP [do not accept \"GNP\" or \"GDP per capita\"][10] This theory holds that currency exchange rates will approach the ratio of prices of identical goods and services in two countries. It can convert GDP between currencies to avoid discrepancies from fluctuating exchange rates.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 18 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about measures used to compare the economies of different countries. For 10 points each: [10] This term denotes the total market value of goods and services produced within a country.",
		"answers": [
			"gross",
			"domestic",
			"product",
			"GDP"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "object permanence[10] This psychologist first studied object permanence in infants, and believed it originated in the sensorimotor stage of his theory of cognitive development.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 10 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The incompleteness of this understanding can result in an a-not-b error. For 10 points each: [10] Name this concept, the continued existence of items that can no longer be seen or otherwise observed. The lack of it may be why some babies are startled by the game of peek-a-boo.",
		"answers": [
			"object",
			"permanence",
			"10",
			"This",
			"psychologist",
			"first",
			"studied",
			"in",
			"infants",
			"and",
			"believed",
			"originated",
			"sensorimotor",
			"stage",
			"his",
			"theory",
			"cognitive",
			"development"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Swahili language[10] In written characters, many African languages such as Xhosa use a character symbolized by an exclamation point. Those sounds are pronounced by making this noise.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Brookwood Invitational Scholars Bowl |2013 | 1 | 20 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about African languages, for 10 points each: [10] This language mostly prominent today in East Africa developed as a result of mixing Bantu, Arabic, and some European languages. In this language, \"hakuna matata\" means no worries, and is generally a wonderful phrase.",
		"answers": [
			"Swahili",
			"language",
			"10",
			"In",
			"written",
			"characters",
			"many",
			"African",
			"languages",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Xhosa",
			"use",
			"character",
			"symbolized",
			"by",
			"an",
			"exclamation",
			"point",
			"Those",
			"sounds",
			"are",
			"pronounced",
			"making",
			"this",
			"noise"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bystander Effect[10] The murder of this New York resident first brought the bystander effect to the attention of researchers, although many details of her death were inaccurately reported.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One experiment investigating this effect involved subjects conversing with a stranger over an intercom, who then proceeded to fake an epileptic seizure. For 10 points each: [10] Name this social phenomenon, in which the presence of greater numbers of people decreases the probability of individuals giving aid to a potential victim.",
		"answers": [
			"Bystander",
			"Effect",
			"10",
			"The",
			"murder",
			"this",
			"New",
			"York",
			"resident",
			"first",
			"brought",
			"bystander",
			"effect",
			"to",
			"attention",
			"researchers",
			"although",
			"many",
			"details",
			"her",
			"death",
			"were",
			"inaccurately",
			"reported"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rats[10] B. F. Skinner trained these animals to play ping pong, and in Skinner's Box, they pecked at a device to release food. Skinner also devised a plan using these birds to guide missiles.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 12 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some animals used in psychological studies and experiments, for 10 points each: [10] John Watson conditioned Little Albert to fear a white one of these rodents. Laboratory types of these rodents generally traverse mazes, and they are slightly larger than mice.",
		"answers": [
			"Rats",
			"10",
			"B",
			"F",
			"Skinner",
			"trained",
			"these",
			"animals",
			"to",
			"play",
			"ping",
			"pong",
			"and",
			"in",
			"Skinner's",
			"Box",
			"they",
			"pecked",
			"at",
			"device",
			"release",
			"food",
			"also",
			"devised",
			"plan",
			"using",
			"birds",
			"guide",
			"missiles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Prisoner's Dilemma[10] Both players choosing to defect is an example of this concept, in which players know the strategies of others and make the best decision for themselves with that knowledge.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 17 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this scenario, two players are given a choice between cooperating and defecting. For 10 points each: [10] Name this situation in game theory in which defecting is the best decision, even though mutual cooperation would lead to the optimal outcome.",
		"answers": [
			"Prisoner's",
			"Dilemma",
			"10",
			"Both",
			"players",
			"choosing",
			"to",
			"defect",
			"an",
			"example",
			"this",
			"concept",
			"in",
			"which",
			"know",
			"strategies",
			"others",
			"and",
			"make",
			"best",
			"decision",
			"for",
			"themselves",
			"with",
			"that",
			"knowledge"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Taxation [accept word forms such as \"taxes\"][10] This curve plots taxation against government revenue, and can be used to find the optimal rate to maximize revenue.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Supply-side economics argues for a lower rate for this economic institution. For 10 points each: [10] Name this method used by the government to raise revenue from sales, property, income, wealth, and payrolls, among others.",
		"answers": [
			"Taxation",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"such",
			"as",
			"taxes",
			"10",
			"This",
			"curve",
			"plots",
			"taxation",
			"against",
			"government",
			"revenue",
			"and",
			"can",
			"be",
			"used",
			"to",
			"find",
			"optimal",
			"rate",
			"maximize"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stanford Prison Experiment[10] Following the Stanford Prison Experiment, Zimbardo published this book, which examines how good people can turn evil.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 16 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One subject in this experiment became known as \"John Wayne\" for his cruelty. For 10 points each: [10] Name this psychological experiment conducted by Philip Zimbardo, in which students were chosen to be either inmates or guards.",
		"answers": [
			"Stanford",
			"Prison",
			"Experiment",
			"10",
			"Following",
			"Zimbardo",
			"published",
			"this",
			"book",
			"which",
			"examines",
			"how",
			"good",
			"people",
			"can",
			"turn",
			"evil"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Maynard Keynes[10] This major work by Keynes was published during the Great Depression, and lays out the framework of his major economic ideas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 1 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He advocated raising taxes to pay for World War II, rather than increased deficit spending, and notably opposed the gold standard. For 10 points each: [10] Name this British economist, whose namesake school of thought holds that aggregate demand influences economic output.",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Maynard",
			"Keynes",
			"10",
			"This",
			"major",
			"work",
			"by",
			"was",
			"published",
			"during",
			"Great",
			"Depression",
			"and",
			"lays",
			"out",
			"framework",
			"his",
			"economic",
			"ideas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "doll[10] This psychologist conducted the Bobo doll experiment, and repeated it with variations in which the children watch films and cartoons of violence.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This type of object was used in an experiment in which an adult yelled phrases like \"Sock him\" and \"Kick him.\" For 10 points each: [10] A Bobo type of what toy was repeatedly hit by an adult as a child watched in an experiment studying observational learning?",
		"answers": [
			"doll",
			"10",
			"This",
			"psychologist",
			"conducted",
			"Bobo",
			"experiment",
			"and",
			"repeated",
			"with",
			"variations",
			"in",
			"which",
			"children",
			"watch",
			"films",
			"cartoons",
			"violence"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Franz Boas[10] Boas founded the anthropology program at this Ivy League university. Located in New York City, this university subsequently held the country's leading anthropology program.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man taught people like Margaret Mead and Zora Neale Hurston. For 10 points each: [10] Name this German-American \"Father of Anthropology\" who argued against racist beliefs in his The Mind of Primitive Man.",
		"answers": [
			"Franz",
			"Boas",
			"10",
			"founded",
			"anthropology",
			"program",
			"at",
			"this",
			"Ivy",
			"League",
			"university",
			"Located",
			"in",
			"New",
			"York",
			"City",
			"subsequently",
			"held",
			"country's",
			"leading"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "bystander effect[10] The bystander effect is sometimes also named for this woman who was murdered while returning to her Queens home. The media account of 38 witnesses who failed to help may have been exaggerated.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 1 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This effect was demonstrated in China in 2011 after the two year old Wang Yue was hit by a van and truck in the street yet ignored by 18 people. For 10 points: [10] Name this effect in which the title people fail to give help in an emergency. As the number of people present increases its strength also increases.",
		"answers": [
			"bystander",
			"effect",
			"10",
			"The",
			"sometimes",
			"also",
			"named",
			"for",
			"this",
			"woman",
			"who",
			"was",
			"murdered",
			"while",
			"returning",
			"to",
			"her",
			"Queens",
			"home",
			"media",
			"account",
			"38",
			"witnesses",
			"failed",
			"help",
			"may",
			"have",
			"been",
			"exaggerated"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "capital [10] The Cobb-Douglas function estimates the output of these entities as a function of capital and labor using two exponents. Modeled as profit maximizers, these producers' optimization concerns determine the supply curve.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 18 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Union leaders and socialists often described this term as being at odds with labor, although they were generally referring to its owners. For 10 points each:  [10] Give this term from economics, which describes the machinery and tools used to produce goods more efficiently. Its 'human' variety is acquired through education and training. ",
		"answers": [
			"capital",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Cobb-Douglas",
			"function",
			"estimates",
			"output",
			"these",
			"entities",
			"as",
			"and",
			"labor",
			"using",
			"two",
			"exponents",
			"Modeled",
			"profit",
			"maximizers",
			"producers'",
			"optimization",
			"concerns",
			"determine",
			"supply",
			"curve"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "coinage or coins[10] Along with banknotes, coins are labeled under this term, which should not be confused with another term that also includes the balances in bank checking and saving accounts.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 10 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Creating a special platinum one of these objects was suggested to avoid hitting the debt ceiling. For 10 points each: [10] Name these objects of value which in America usually have denominations under a dollar. Quarters and dimes are examples.",
		"answers": [
			"coinage",
			"coins",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Social Darwinism (accept word forms)[10] Darwin was influenced by the 1798 An Essay on the Principle of Population by this man, which contrasted the geometric growth of population and the arithmetic growth of food supply. The epithet 'dismal science' for economics was coined based on a work by this man.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This idea, loosely based on evolutionary principles, was first applied to the economic world by Joseph Fisher, and was popularized by Richard Hofstadter. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this concept, defined by the phrase \"survival of the fittest\". ",
		"answers": [
			"Social",
			"Darwinism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"Darwin",
			"was",
			"influenced",
			"by",
			"1798",
			"An",
			"Essay",
			"Principle",
			"Population",
			"this",
			"man",
			"which",
			"contrasted",
			"geometric",
			"growth",
			"population",
			"and",
			"arithmetic",
			"food",
			"supply",
			"The",
			"epithet",
			"'dismal",
			"science'",
			"for",
			"economics",
			"coined",
			"based",
			"work"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "monopoly (accept word forms)[10] The reverse of the monopoly is this structure characterized by a single buyer and many sellers. Government contracts are an example.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 2 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some different economic markets, for 10 points each: [10] Competition is diminished in this type of market in which a single seller dominates the market.",
		"answers": [
			"monopoly",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"The",
			"reverse",
			"this",
			"structure",
			"characterized",
			"by",
			"single",
			"buyer",
			"and",
			"many",
			"sellers",
			"Government",
			"contracts",
			"are",
			"an",
			"example"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "monopoly (accept word forms)[10] The reverse of the monopoly is this structure characterized by a single buyer and many sellers. Government contracts are an example.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 2 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some different economic markets, for 10 points each: [10] Competition is diminished in this type of market in which a single seller dominates the market.",
		"answers": [
			"monopoly",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"The",
			"reverse",
			"this",
			"structure",
			"characterized",
			"by",
			"single",
			"buyer",
			"and",
			"many",
			"sellers",
			"Government",
			"contracts",
			"are",
			"an",
			"example"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "memory[10] Many psychoanalysts have proposed that humans perform this action, in which painful memories are submerged in the subconscious.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Elizabeth Loftus showed that this process can be tricked and manipulated. For 10 points each: [10] Name this human ability in which information is stored, retrieved, and recalled. The short term form is often called its \"working\" form.",
		"answers": [
			"memory",
			"10",
			"Many",
			"psychoanalysts",
			"have",
			"proposed",
			"that",
			"humans",
			"perform",
			"this",
			"action",
			"in",
			"which",
			"painful",
			"memories",
			"are",
			"submerged",
			"subconscious"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Milton Friedman [10] This man drew up a plan for Bolivia fiscal reform in 1985. He has argued global poverty can be eliminated through foreign aid in works such as The End of Poverty and Common Wealth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 2 | 10 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  Name this economists and economic policies who influenced Latin America, for 10 points each:  [10] This man taught the \"Money and Banking Workshop\" to Chilean economists that became influential in Augusto Pinochet's government. This Chicago economist promoted the free market in books like Capitalism and Freedom and the TV program Free to Choose. ",
		"answers": [
			"Milton",
			"Friedman",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"drew",
			"up",
			"plan",
			"for",
			"Bolivia",
			"fiscal",
			"reform",
			"in",
			"1985",
			"He",
			"has",
			"argued",
			"global",
			"poverty",
			"can",
			"be",
			"eliminated",
			"through",
			"foreign",
			"aid",
			"works",
			"such",
			"as",
			"The",
			"End",
			"Poverty",
			"and",
			"Common",
			"Wealth"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "economic rent[10]  This author of An Inquiry Into the Nature and Progress of Rent pointed out the difference between arithmetically growing resources and exponentially increasing population.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 3 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This concept describes the cost of buying into producing a certain good. Examples include the cost of joining a medieval guild, government royalties, or patent and license costs.",
		"answers": [
			"economic",
			"rent",
			"10",
			"This",
			"author",
			"An",
			"Inquiry",
			"Into",
			"Nature",
			"and",
			"Progress",
			"Rent",
			"pointed",
			"out",
			"difference",
			"between",
			"arithmetically",
			"growing",
			"resources",
			"exponentially",
			"increasing",
			"population"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigmund Freud [or Sigismund Schlomo Freud][10]  Freud proposed that fixations with this second stage in psychosexual development would cause either a destructive and messy personality or a rigid and compulsive personality.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 6 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This psychologist postulated the existence of the mind as an id, ego, and superego in his Beyond the Pleasure Principle.",
		"answers": [
			"Sigmund",
			"Freud",
			"Sigismund",
			"Schlomo",
			"10",
			"proposed",
			"that",
			"fixations",
			"with",
			"this",
			"second",
			"stage",
			"in",
			"psychosexual",
			"development",
			"would",
			"cause",
			"destructive",
			"and",
			"messy",
			"personality",
			"rigid",
			"compulsive"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "artificial intelligence [accept AI or machine intelligence][10]  One method of assessing AI is this test, which an AI can pass if their behavior is indistinguishable from that of a human.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 10 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this concept that refers to a machine's ability to reason, plan, learn, and emulate other aspects of human cognition.",
		"answers": [
			"artificial",
			"intelligence",
			"AI",
			"machine",
			"10",
			"One",
			"method",
			"assessing",
			"this",
			"test",
			"which",
			"an",
			"can",
			"pass",
			"if",
			"their",
			"behavior",
			"indistinguishable",
			"from",
			"that",
			"human"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "magic[10]  This anthropologist suggested that societies first believed in magic, before progressing to religion and science, in his tome of comparative mythology, The Golden Bough.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 20 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this concept which, along with \"Coral Gardens,\" titles a Malinowski book which analyzes agricultural practices of Trobriand Islanders. In \"A General Theory of\" this concept, Mauss contrasts it with religion.",
		"answers": [
			"magic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"anthropologist",
			"suggested",
			"that",
			"societies",
			"first",
			"believed",
			"in",
			"progressing",
			"to",
			"religion",
			"and",
			"science",
			"his",
			"tome",
			"comparative",
			"mythology",
			"The",
			"Golden",
			"Bough"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Souls of Black Folk[10]  The Souls of Black Folk is a seminal work in sociology by this editor of The Crisis. A rival of Booker T. Washington, he introduced the idea of the \"talented tenth,\" and founded the Niagara movement.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 11 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this sociological work, a collection of essays on African-American identity. It argues that the happy black slave is a flawed image created by whites, and describes a \"veil\" between black and white perspectives.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Souls",
			"Black",
			"Folk",
			"10",
			"seminal",
			"work",
			"in",
			"sociology",
			"by",
			"this",
			"editor",
			"Crisis",
			"A",
			"rival",
			"Booker",
			"T",
			"Washington",
			"he",
			"introduced",
			"idea",
			"talented",
			"tenth",
			"and",
			"founded",
			"Niagara",
			"movement"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "psychoanalysis[10]  Unconditional positive regard is a trait of a therapist who uses person-centered therapy, a technique developed by this humanistic psychologist. He is the author of On Becoming a Person.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 17 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This approach emphasizes the effect of unconscious factors and childhood experiences on current behaviors. Developers of this approach include Sigmund Freud and Jacques Lacan.",
		"answers": [
			"psychoanalysis",
			"10",
			"Unconditional",
			"positive",
			"regard",
			"trait",
			"therapist",
			"who",
			"uses",
			"person-centered",
			"therapy",
			"technique",
			"developed",
			"by",
			"this",
			"humanistic",
			"psychologist",
			"He",
			"author",
			"On",
			"Becoming",
			"Person"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "depression [or major depressive disorder][10]  Zoloft treats depression by selectively inhibiting the reuptake of this neurotransmitter. Derived from tryptophan, it has also been linked to schizophrenia and OCD.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 16 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This disorder alternates with mania in bipolar disorder. Its symptoms include social withdrawal, appetite and sleep changes, fatigue, and persistent disinterest or general sadness.",
		"answers": [
			"depression",
			"major",
			"depressive",
			"disorder",
			"10",
			"Zoloft",
			"treats",
			"by",
			"selectively",
			"inhibiting",
			"reuptake",
			"this",
			"neurotransmitter",
			"Derived",
			"from",
			"tryptophan",
			"has",
			"also",
			"been",
			"linked",
			"to",
			"schizophrenia",
			"and",
			"OCD"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stanford prison experiment[10]  This psychology professor conducted the Stanford prison experiment and wrote The Time Paradox.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round09.docx | 15 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this experiment was intended to show the effects of authority, but was aborted six days after its inception after guards began to physically and psychologically abuse other participants.",
		"answers": [
			"Stanford",
			"prison",
			"experiment",
			"10",
			"This",
			"psychology",
			"professor",
			"conducted",
			"and",
			"wrote",
			"The",
			"Time",
			"Paradox"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "trolley problem[10]  As a form of consequentialism, this ethical theory would have the agent flip the switch to maximize the net happiness for the greatest number.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 3 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this thought experiment proposed by Philippa Foot which asks whether it is ethical to flip a track switch to kill one man instead of five.",
		"answers": [
			"trolley",
			"problem",
			"10",
			"As",
			"form",
			"consequentialism",
			"this",
			"ethical",
			"theory",
			"would",
			"have",
			"agent",
			"flip",
			"switch",
			"to",
			"maximize",
			"net",
			"happiness",
			"for",
			"greatest",
			"number"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gestaltism [or Gestalt theory][10]  This theory that emerged from Gestalt theory holds that there exist two of its namesake entities in memory, verbatim and gist. It also attempts to explain risky decision making.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 9 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This theory claims that the whole is greater than its parts. Central to this theory is the law of pragnanz which claims that we try to find order and regularity in our sensations.",
		"answers": [
			"Gestaltism",
			"Gestalt",
			"theory",
			"10",
			"This",
			"that",
			"emerged",
			"from",
			"holds",
			"there",
			"exist",
			"two",
			"its",
			"namesake",
			"entities",
			"in",
			"memory",
			"verbatim",
			"and",
			"gist",
			"It",
			"also",
			"attempts",
			"to",
			"explain",
			"risky",
			"decision",
			"making"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gender[10]  This writer tackled \"the problem that has no name\" and, in The Feminine Mystique, described the title concept as the illusion that women were fulfilled through marriage and housework.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 15 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this psychological concept that refers to characteristics and roles associated with sex. Unlike sex, which is usually considered biologically determined, this concept can be self-determined.",
		"answers": [
			"gender",
			"10",
			"This",
			"writer",
			"tackled",
			"problem",
			"that",
			"has",
			"no",
			"name",
			"and",
			"in",
			"The",
			"Feminine",
			"Mystique",
			"described",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"as",
			"illusion",
			"women",
			"were",
			"fulfilled",
			"through",
			"marriage",
			"housework"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sapir-Whorf hypothesis[10]  This MIT professor of linguistics and author of Syntactic Structures argued for a universal grammar, meaning that surface differences in languages do not affect cognition, contrary to the Sapir-Whorf hypothesis.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 12 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This principle of linguistic relativity has a strong form, which holds that thought is determined by language, and a weak form, stating that thought is only influenced, not limited, by language.",
		"answers": [
			"Sapir-Whorf",
			"hypothesis",
			"10",
			"This",
			"MIT",
			"professor",
			"linguistics",
			"and",
			"author",
			"Syntactic",
			"Structures",
			"argued",
			"for",
			"universal",
			"grammar",
			"meaning",
			"that",
			"surface",
			"differences",
			"in",
			"languages"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "taxes[10]  At tax rates of 0 and 100 percent, this curve assumes that government revenue is zero. Its maxima represents the optimal tax rate.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 20 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  These entities can be progressive or regressive. Before becoming savings, income is partitioned such that these are taken out and used to fund public-sector expenditures.",
		"answers": [
			"taxes",
			"10",
			"At",
			"tax",
			"rates",
			"0",
			"and",
			"100",
			"percent",
			"this",
			"curve",
			"assumes",
			"that",
			"government",
			"revenue",
			"zero",
			"Its",
			"maxima",
			"represents",
			"optimal",
			"rate"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ruth Benedict[10]  This father of modern anthropology taught Ruth Benedict and Margaret Mead. His own studies of the Kwakiutl led him to develop his ideas of cultural relativism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 16 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this anthropologist whose Patterns of Culture expressed her views of cultural relativism. She wrote about the Japanese guilt and shame cultures in The Chrysanthemum and the Sword.",
		"answers": [
			"Ruth",
			"Benedict",
			"10",
			"This",
			"father",
			"modern",
			"anthropology",
			"taught",
			"and",
			"Margaret",
			"Mead",
			"His",
			"own",
			"studies",
			"Kwakiutl",
			"led",
			"him",
			"to",
			"develop",
			"his",
			"ideas",
			"cultural",
			"relativism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "bald eagle (accept Haliaeetus leucocephalus)[10]  This woman's book Silent Spring raised awareness for the plight of the bald eagle population and the impact of DDT on other birds. She was a marine biologist, and also wrote The Sea Around Us.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 14 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This national bird of the United States is named for its white plumage on the top of its head and not for its lack of hair. It faced near-extinction in the middle of the 20th century.",
		"answers": [
			"bald",
			"eagle",
			"Haliaeetus",
			"leucocephalus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"woman's",
			"book",
			"Silent",
			"Spring",
			"raised",
			"awareness",
			"for",
			"plight",
			"population",
			"and",
			"impact",
			"DDT",
			"other",
			"birds",
			"She",
			"was",
			"marine",
			"biologist",
			"also",
			"wrote",
			"The",
			"Sea",
			"Around",
			"Us"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Benghazi[10]  This UN Ambassador was considered for appointment to Secretary of State in President Obama's second term, but withdrew her name due to the expected controversy over the Benghazi attacks.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 4 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this city, in which a September 11, 2012 attack on the US Embassy led to the death of Ambassador Chris Stevens.",
		"answers": [
			"Benghazi",
			"10",
			"This",
			"UN",
			"Ambassador",
			"was",
			"considered",
			"for",
			"appointment",
			"to",
			"Secretary",
			"State",
			"in",
			"President",
			"Obama's",
			"second",
			"term",
			"but",
			"withdrew",
			"her",
			"name",
			"due",
			"expected",
			"controversy",
			"over",
			"attacks"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "production possibility frontier (or production possibility curve)[10]  The slope at a given point on the PPF is the amount of one good to produce more of the other, the marginal opportunity type of this entity. The next-best alternative given up in a decision is referred to as the opportunity-this.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 7 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this curve from economics which plots the maximum quantity of one good that can be produced against another, such as the trade-off between guns and butter.",
		"answers": [
			"production",
			"possibility",
			"frontier",
			"curve",
			"10",
			"The",
			"slope",
			"at",
			"given",
			"point",
			"PPF",
			"amount",
			"one",
			"good",
			"to",
			"produce",
			"more",
			"other",
			"marginal",
			"opportunity",
			"type",
			"this",
			"entity",
			"next-best",
			"alternative",
			"up",
			"in",
			"decision",
			"referred",
			"as",
			"opportunity-this"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "polygraph machines[10]  Polygraph tests are typically not permitted as evidence in court due to the prevalence of these cases, where people who tell the truth are marked as liars. This term also describes people mistakenly diagnosed with a disease.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 9 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name these machines which can be used to detect lies.",
		"answers": [
			"polygraph",
			"machines",
			"10",
			"Polygraph",
			"tests",
			"are",
			"typically"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "personality[10]  Carl Jung's Psychological Types provided the basis for this personality test. It uses a combination of four dichotomies, such as sensing versus intuition and thinking versus feeling.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 21 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this term which describes the pattern of thoughts, emotions, and behaviors in people. Temperament is considered the innate component of it.",
		"answers": [
			"personality",
			"10",
			"Carl",
			"Jung's",
			"Psychological",
			"Types",
			"provided",
			"basis",
			"for",
			"this",
			"test",
			"It",
			"uses",
			"combination",
			"four",
			"dichotomies",
			"such",
			"as",
			"sensing",
			"versus",
			"intuition",
			"and",
			"thinking",
			"feeling"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "bystander effect (accept Kitty Genovese effect, but do not reveal if not given)[10]  This phenomenon is thought to magnify the bystander effect in large groups. It maintains that people are discouraged from action by the inaction of others around them.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 12 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this effect in which the presence of others makes people less likely to react in emergency situations.",
		"answers": [
			"bystander",
			"effect",
			"Kitty",
			"Genovese",
			"but"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Capitalism and Freedom[10]  This economist wrote Capitalism and Freedom and co-authored Free to Choose with his wife. He advocated for monetarism and criticized the Phillips curve with the natural rate of unemployment.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 5 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this work which sought to define the liberal in European Enlightenment terms. It advocates replacing the Bretton Woods system with a floating exchange rate system.",
		"answers": [
			"Capitalism",
			"and",
			"Freedom",
			"10",
			"This",
			"economist",
			"wrote",
			"co-authored",
			"Free",
			"to",
			"Choose",
			"with",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"He",
			"advocated",
			"for",
			"monetarism",
			"criticized",
			"Phillips",
			"curve",
			"natural",
			"rate",
			"unemployment"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ivan Pavlov[10]  Pavlov championed this branch of behaviorism in which subjects learn to anticipate events by pairing two or more stimuli that are presented in close succession.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 10 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Russian psychologist who more famously monitored salivation to show that dogs can learn to associate the ringing of a bell, with the arrival of food.",
		"answers": [
			"Ivan",
			"Pavlov",
			"10",
			"championed",
			"this",
			"branch",
			"behaviorism",
			"in",
			"which",
			"subjects",
			"learn",
			"to",
			"anticipate",
			"events",
			"by",
			"pairing",
			"two",
			"more",
			"stimuli",
			"that",
			"are",
			"presented",
			"close",
			"succession"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Carl Jung[10]  Jung believed that these universal symbols were used to channel human experience and resulted in typical patterns of behavior.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 20 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This psychoanalyst broke with Freud over his assertion that humanity has a collective unconscious. He described the anima and animus as representing the feminine and masculine parts of personality.",
		"answers": [
			"Carl",
			"Jung",
			"10",
			"believed",
			"that",
			"these",
			"universal",
			"symbols",
			"were",
			"used",
			"to",
			"channel",
			"human",
			"experience",
			"and",
			"resulted",
			"in",
			"typical",
			"patterns",
			"behavior"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "availability heuristic[10] This other cognitive bias is the tendency for people to pay attention to information which supports their  preconcieved notions and screen out contradictory information.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many people answer wrongly when asked whether there are more English words that start with K or more words  with K as their third letter. For 10 points each: [10] This heuristic is exemplified by picking the first answer even though more English words have K as their third  letter. This bias makes people think an event is more probable based on how readily an example comes to mind.",
		"answers": [
			"availability",
			"heuristic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"cognitive",
			"bias",
			"tendency",
			"for",
			"people",
			"to",
			"pay",
			"attention",
			"information",
			"which",
			"supports",
			"their",
			"preconcieved"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "availability heuristic[10] This other cognitive bias is the tendency for people to pay attention to information which supports their  preconcieved notions and screen out contradictory information.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many people answer wrongly when asked whether there are more English words that start with K or more words  with K as their third letter. For 10 points each: [10] This heuristic is exemplified by picking the first answer even though more English words have K as their third  letter. This bias makes people think an event is more probable based on how readily an example comes to mind.",
		"answers": [
			"availability",
			"heuristic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"cognitive",
			"bias",
			"tendency",
			"for",
			"people",
			"to",
			"pay",
			"attention",
			"information",
			"which",
			"supports",
			"their",
			"preconcieved"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "demand curve[10] The slope of the demand curve is related to this measure, defined as the ratio of percentage change in demand  to percentage change in price. It is 0 for a vertical demand curve and infinite for a horizontal demand curve.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 16 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: As income rises, it shifts outward for normal goods and inward for inferior goods. For 10 points each: [10] Name this usually downward-sloping curve that plots the amount of a good that consumers will buy at a given  price.",
		"answers": [
			"demand",
			"curve",
			"10",
			"The",
			"slope",
			"related",
			"to",
			"this",
			"measure",
			"defined",
			"as",
			"ratio",
			"percentage",
			"change",
			"in",
			"price",
			"It",
			"0",
			"for",
			"vertical",
			"and",
			"infinite",
			"horizontal"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "learned helplessness[10] In this questionably ethical experiment, Watson and Rayner aversively conditioned a baby to fear rats and other  furry things.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name some things about conditioning: [10] The inability to avoid adverse events can result in this feeling of futility. Even if the opportunity to escape is  reintroduced, the learner will often still resign themselves.",
		"answers": [
			"learned",
			"helplessness",
			"10",
			"In",
			"this",
			"questionably",
			"ethical",
			"experiment",
			"Watson",
			"and",
			"Rayner",
			"aversively",
			"conditioned",
			"baby",
			"to",
			"fear",
			"rats",
			"other",
			"furry",
			"things"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "William James[10] William James and C. S. Peirce founded this philosophical school whose core maxim emphasizes the  importance of clear concepts and practical consequences.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 8 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He critiqued Spinoza and Hume in \"The Sentiment of Rationality.\" For 10 points each: [10] Identify this philosopher who described the \"stream of thought\" in Principles of Psychology and discussed  mysticism in The Varieties of Religious Experience.",
		"answers": [
			"William",
			"James",
			"10",
			"and",
			"C",
			"S",
			"Peirce",
			"founded",
			"this",
			"philosophical",
			"school",
			"whose",
			"core",
			"maxim",
			"emphasizes",
			"importance",
			"clear",
			"concepts",
			"practical",
			"consequences"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "money [do not accept \"currency\"][10] The Federal Reserve sets this minimum amount of money that a bank must retain at the end of each day. It is  currently 10% of the bank's net transactions. The money multiplier is the reciprocal of this quantity.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 12 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The fiat type of this entity derives its value from its declaration as \"legal tender\" by the government. For 10  points each: [10] Give this general term for an object that can be accepted as payment for a good or service. Most of its M1 (\"M  one\") supply is held in banks.",
		"answers": [
			"money"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Edward Sapir[10] In an influential study in linguistic relativity, Berlin and Kay studied different languages' words for these concepts, classifying English as \"Stage VII\" since it has separate words for purple, pink, orange, and gray.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 12 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man helped record the Yahi language from its last living member, a man called Ishi. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Yale linguist who created a comprehensive classification of Native American languages for the Encyclopedia Britannica. He inspired his student Benjamin Whorf to develop the theory of linguistic relativity.",
		"answers": [
			"Edward",
			"Sapir",
			"10",
			"In",
			"an",
			"influential",
			"study",
			"in",
			"linguistic",
			"relativity",
			"Berlin",
			"and",
			"Kay",
			"studied",
			"different",
			"languages'",
			"words",
			"for",
			"these",
			"concepts",
			"classifying",
			"English",
			"as",
			"Stage",
			"VII",
			"since",
			"has",
			"separate",
			"purple",
			"pink",
			"orange",
			"gray"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "mythology [or mythologies][10] This French anthropologist developed his structuralist approach to myth in Mythologiques, which includes The Raw and the Cooked. He also wrote the memoir Tristes Tropiques and The Elementary Structures of Kinship.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Robert Graves subtitled his The White Goddess \"a Historical Grammar of Poetic\" this, and Roland Barthes examined \"The World of Wrestling\" and \"Toys\" in a book named for a set of these. For 10 points each: [10] Name this concept whose Zuni variety titles an anthropological survey by Ruth Benedict.",
		"answers": [
			"mythology",
			"mythologies",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"anthropologist",
			"developed",
			"his",
			"structuralist",
			"approach",
			"to",
			"myth",
			"in",
			"Mythologiques",
			"which",
			"includes",
			"The",
			"Raw",
			"and",
			"Cooked",
			"He",
			"also",
			"wrote",
			"memoir",
			"Tristes",
			"Tropiques",
			"Elementary",
			"Structures",
			"Kinship"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Max Weber[10] Weber proposed that the Protestant ethic was closely related to \"the spirit of\" this economic system based on free markets, which communists oppose.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 6 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This German author of The Religion of China, The Religion of India, and Economy and Society delineated rational-legal, traditional, and charismatic types of authority. For 10 points each: [10] Name this sociologist who suggested that Calvinism was responsible for the appearance of a novel economic system in Northern Europe.",
		"answers": [
			"Max",
			"Weber",
			"10",
			"proposed",
			"that",
			"Protestant",
			"ethic",
			"was",
			"closely",
			"related",
			"to",
			"spirit",
			"this",
			"economic",
			"system",
			"based",
			"free",
			"markets",
			"which",
			"communists",
			"oppose"
		]
	}
]